const flashcardsData = [
    {
        question: "Is the most common dryer used which consist of rotating cylinder inside which the materials flow while getting in contact with hot gas.",
        choices: [
            "A. Tower dryer",
            "B. Centrifugal dryer",
            "C. Tray dryer",
            "D. Rotary dryer"
        ],
        answer: "D. Rotary dryer"
    },
    {
        question: "The total heat of the air is a function of",
        choices: [
            "A. WB temperature",
            "B. DP temperature",
            "C. DB temperature",
            "D. WB depression"
        ],
        answer: "A. WB temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the ratio of the mass of water-vapor in air and the mass of air if it is saturated is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. humidity ratio",
            "B. mass ratio",
            "C. vapor ratio",
            "D. Relative humidity"
        ],
        answer: "D. Relative humidity"
    },
    {
        question: "The hands feel painfully cold when the skin temperature reaches",
        choices: [
            "A. 8 deg C",
            "B. 10 deg C",
            "C. 12 deg C",
            "D. 14 deg C"
        ],
        answer: "B. 10 deg C"
    },
    {
        question: "The refrigerant used in steam jet cooling is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Steam",
            "B. R-11",
            "C. Ammonia",
            "D. Water"
        ],
        answer: "D. Water"
    },
    {
        question: "The total heat of the air is a function of",
        choices: [
            "A. WB temperature",
            "B. DP temperature",
            "C. DB temperature",
            "D. WB depression"
        ],
        answer: "A. WB temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "Boiling point of Freon-12 at atmospheric pressure is:",
        choices: [
            "A. 21 oF",
            "B. 15 oF",
            "C. 5 oF",
            "D. 28 oF"
        ],
        answer: "A. 21 oF"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a type of water cooled condenser in refrigeration?",
        choices: [
            "A. Double pipe",
            "B. Double shell",
            "C. Shell and coil",
            "D. Shell and tube"
        ],
        answer: "B. Double shell"
    },
    {
        question: "Component of absorption refrigeration system in which the solution is cooled by cooling water.",
        choices: [
            "A. Rectifier",
            "B. Generator",
            "C. Evaporator",
            "D. Absorber"
        ],
        answer: "D. Absorber"
    },
    {
        question: "Cascade refrigeration cycle is often used in industrial process where objects must be cooled to temperature below:",
        choices: [
            "A. -46 oC",
            "B. -56 oC",
            "C. -66 oC",
            "D. -76 oC"
        ],
        answer: "A. -46 oC"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of refrigerant control designed to maintain a pressure difference while the compressor is operating.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermostatic expansion valve",
            "B. Automatic expansion valve",
            "C. Using low side float flooded system",
            "D. Capillary tube"
        ],
        answer: "D. Capillary tube"
    },
    {
        question: "As a rule of thumb, for a specified amount of compressed air, the power consumption of the compressor decreases by __________ for each 3oC drop in the temperature inlet air to the compressor.",
        choices: [
            "A. 1 percent",
            "B. 1.5 percent",
            "C. 2 percent",
            "D. 2.5 percent"
        ],
        answer: "A. 1 percent"
    },
    {
        question: "Modern way of detecting air compressor leak is by using",
        choices: [
            "A. Soup and water",
            "B. Air leak detector",
            "C. Acoustic leak detector",
            "D. Ammonia leak detector"
        ],
        answer: "C. Acoustic leak detector"
    },
    {
        question: "For foundation of stacks, the maximum pressure on the soil is equal to the pressure due to the weight and the _______.",
        choices: [
            "A. Soil movement",
            "B. Wind movement",
            "C. Ground movement",
            "D. Engine movement"
        ],
        answer: "B. Wind movement"
    },
    {
        question: "Foundation bolts of specified size should be used and surrounded by a pipe sleeve with an inside diameter of at least",
        choices: [
            "A. 3 times the diameter of engine bolt",
            "B. 3 times the diameter of anchor bolt",
            "C. 2 times the diameter of engine bolt",
            "D. 2 times the diameter of anchor bolt"
        ],
        answer: "B. 3 times the diameter of anchor bolt"
    },
    {
        question: "For multi stage compression of an ideal Brayton cycle, the back work ratio will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of turbine that has a specific speed below 5.",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbine",
            "B. Propeller turbine",
            "C. Francis turbine",
            "D. Deriaz turbine"
        ],
        answer: "A. Impulse turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "A high discharge type of turbine",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbine",
            "B. Francis turbine",
            "C. Propeller turbine",
            "D. Deriaz turbine"
        ],
        answer: "C. Propeller turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "Use to minimize the speed rise due to a sudden load rejection",
        choices: [
            "A. needle valve",
            "B. wicket gate",
            "C. Shut-off valve",
            "D. jet deflector"
        ],
        answer: "D. jet deflector"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the speed of a turbine when the head on the turbine is one meter.",
        choices: [
            "A. specific speed",
            "B. rated speed",
            "C. utilized speed",
            "D. unit speed"
        ],
        answer: "D. unit speed"
    },
    {
        question: "Is a fluid property which refers to the intermolecular attraction by which the separate particles of the fluid are held together.",
        choices: [
            "A. Cohesion",
            "B. Adhesion",
            "C. Surface tension",
            "D. hypertension"
        ],
        answer: "A. Cohesion"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT the cause of black smoke in diesel engine?",
        choices: [
            "A. fuel valve open too long",
            "B. high compression pressure",
            "C. carbon in exhaust pipe",
            "D. overload on engine"
        ],
        answer: "B. high compression pressure"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not a method of starting a diesel engine?",
        choices: [
            "A. Manual: rope, crank and kick",
            "B. Electric (battery)",
            "C. Compressed air",
            "D. Using another generator"
        ],
        answer: "D. Using another generator"
    },
    {
        question: "Two-stroke engine performs ______ to complete one cycle.",
        choices: [
            "A. suction and discharge stroke",
            "B. power and exhaust stroke",
            "C. compression and power stroke",
            "D. suction and exhaust stroke"
        ],
        answer: "C. compression and power stroke"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of geothermal plant used when there is a presence of brine extracted from underground",
        choices: [
            "A. Dry geothermal plant",
            "B. Double-flash geothermal plant",
            "C. Single flash geothermal plant",
            "D. Binary geothermal plant"
        ],
        answer: "D. Binary geothermal plant"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the most important safety device on the power boiler.",
        choices: [
            "A. Check valve",
            "B. Gate valve",
            "C. Safety valve",
            "D. Globe valve"
        ],
        answer: "C. Safety valve"
    },
    {
        question: "During hydrostatic test, the safety valves should be",
        choices: [
            "A. removed",
            "B. open",
            "C. closed",
            "D. partially closed"
        ],
        answer: "A. removed"
    },
    {
        question: "Where deaerating heaters are not employed, it is recommended that the temperature of the feed water be not less than ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. 197 OC",
            "B. 102 OC",
            "C. 104 OC",
            "D. 106 OC"
        ],
        answer: "A. 197 OC"
    },
    {
        question: "Is a reaction during which chemical energy is released in the form of heat.",
        choices: [
            "A. Cosmic reaction",
            "B. Ethnic reaction",
            "C. Endothermic reaction",
            "D. Exothermic reaction"
        ],
        answer: "D. Exothermic reaction"
    },
    {
        question: "By reheating the steam in an ideal Ranking cycle the heat rejected will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increase"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the boiler pressure in Rankine cycle the moisture content at boiler exit will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increase"
    },
    {
        question: "Presently the highest steam temperature allowed at the turbine inlet is about ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. 340 OC",
            "B. 520 OC",
            "C. 620 OC",
            "D. 1020 OC"
        ],
        answer: "C. 620 OC"
    },
    {
        question: "Two most common gases employed in Stirling and Ericsson cycles are:",
        choices: [
            "A. Air and helium",
            "B. Oxygen and helium",
            "C. Hydrogen and helium",
            "D. Nitrogen and helium"
        ],
        answer: "C. Hydrogen and helium"
    },
    {
        question: "In most common designs of Gas turbine, the pressure ratio ranges from",
        choices: [
            "A. 10 to 12",
            "B. 11 to 16",
            "C. 12 to 18",
            "D. 15 to 20"
        ],
        answer: "B. 11 to 16"
    },
    {
        question: "In Brayton cycle, the heat is transformed during what process?",
        choices: [
            "A. constant temperature",
            "B. isentropic process",
            "C. isobaric process",
            "D. isochoric process"
        ],
        answer: "C. isobaric process"
    },
    {
        question: "The fuel injection process in diesel engine starts when the piston ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. is at the TDC",
            "B. leaving TDC",
            "C. approaches TDC",
            "D. halfway of the stroke"
        ],
        answer: "C. approaches TDC"
    },
    {
        question: "If the cut-off ratio of diesel cycle increases, the cycle efficiency will",
        choices: [
            "A. decrease",
            "B. increase",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "The fuel used in a power plant that is used during peak periods.",
        choices: [
            "A. gas",
            "B. solid",
            "C. liquid",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. liquid"
    },
    {
        question: "Typical compression ratio of Otto cycle is",
        choices: [
            "A. 6",
            "B. 8",
            "C. 10",
            "D. 12"
        ],
        answer: "B. 8"
    },
    {
        question: "If Joule Thompson coefficient is equal to zero, then the process will become",
        choices: [
            "A. isentropic",
            "B. isenthalpic",
            "C. isobaric",
            "D. isothermal"
        ],
        answer: "D. isothermal"
    },
    {
        question: "If the fluid passed through a nozzle its entropy will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerants consisting of mixtures of two or more different chemical compounds, often used individually as refrigerants for other applications.",
        choices: [
            "A. suspension",
            "B. compound reaction",
            "C. slicing",
            "D. mixing of refrigerants"
        ],
        answer: "C. slicing"
    },
    {
        question: "Pairs of mating stop valves that allow sections of a system to be joined before opening these valves or separated after closing them",
        choices: [
            "A. Check valve",
            "B. Gate valve",
            "C. Safety valve",
            "D. Companion valve"
        ],
        answer: "D. Companion valve"
    },
    {
        question: "An enclosed passageway that limits travel to a single path.",
        choices: [
            "A. corridor",
            "B. hallway",
            "C. lobby",
            "D. tunnel"
        ],
        answer: "A. corridor"
    },
    {
        question: "For immediate dangerous to life or health (IDHL), the maximum concentration from which unprotected persons are able to escape within ______ without escape-impairing symptoms or irreversible health.",
        choices: [
            "A. 15 minutes",
            "B. 1 minutes",
            "C. 20 minutes",
            "D. 30 minutes"
        ],
        answer: "D. 30 minutes"
    },
    {
        question: "Is also known as deaerator.",
        choices: [
            "A. open heater",
            "B. closed heater",
            "C. reheat heater",
            "D. regenerative heater"
        ],
        answer: "A. open heater"
    },
    {
        question: "The volume as determined from internal dimensions of the container with no allowance for the volume of internal parts.",
        choices: [
            "A. internal allowance volume",
            "B. internal gross volume",
            "C. internal interference volume",
            "D. internal fits volume"
        ],
        answer: "B. internal gross volume"
    },
    {
        question: "A waiting room or large hallway serving as a waiting room.",
        choices: [
            "A. terrace",
            "B. rest room",
            "C. compound room",
            "D. lobby"
        ],
        answer: "D. lobby"
    },
    {
        question: "A continuous and unobstructed path of travel from any point in a building or structure to a public way.",
        choices: [
            "A. average of aggress",
            "B. mean of aggress",
            "C. halfway of aggress",
            "D. pathway of aggress"
        ],
        answer: "B. mean of aggress"
    },
    {
        question: "Any device or portion of the equipment used to increase refrigerant pressure.",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure relief device",
            "B. pressure-imposing element",
            "C. pressure lift device",
            "D. pressure limiting device"
        ],
        answer: "B. pressure-imposing element"
    },
    {
        question: "The quantity of refrigerant stored at some point is the refrigeration system for operational, service, or standby purposes.",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure vessel",
            "B. pumpdown charge",
            "C. liquid receiver",
            "D. accumulator"
        ],
        answer: "B. pumpdown charge"
    },
    {
        question: "Secondary refrigerant is a liquid used for the transmission of heat, without a change of state, and having no flash point or a flash point above ______ as determined from ASTM.",
        choices: [
            "A. 150 deg F",
            "B. 160 deg F",
            "C. 180 deg F",
            "D. 200 deg F"
        ],
        answer: "A. 150 deg F"
    },
    {
        question: "A service valve for dual pressure-relief devices that allows using one device while isolating the other from the system, maintaining one valve in operation at all times.",
        choices: [
            "A. three-way valve",
            "B. two-way valve",
            "C. one-way valve",
            "D. four-way valve"
        ],
        answer: "A. three-way valve"
    },
    {
        question: "Tubing that is unenclosed and therefore exposed to crushing, abrasion, puncture, or similar damage after installation.",
        choices: [
            "A. protected tubing",
            "B. bare tubing",
            "C. open tubing",
            "D. unprotected tubing"
        ],
        answer: "D. unprotected tubing"
    },
    {
        question: "Refers to blends comprising multiple components of different volatile that, when used in refrigeration cycles, change volumetric composition and saturation temperature as they evaporate (boil) or condense at constant pressure.",
        choices: [
            "A. zeolite",
            "B. blending",
            "C. composition",
            "D. zestropic"
        ],
        answer: "D. zestropic"
    },
    {
        question: "Is a premises or that portion of a premise from which, because they are disabled, debilitated, or confined, occupants cannot readily leave without the assistance of others.",
        choices: [
            "A. Institutional occupancy",
            "B. Public assembly occupancy",
            "C. Residential occupancy",
            "D. Commercial occupancy"
        ],
        answer: "A. Institutional occupancy"
    },
    {
        question: "Is one in which a secondary coolant is in direct contact with the air or other substance to be cooled or heated.",
        choices: [
            "A. double indirect open spray system",
            "B. Indirect open spray system",
            "C. Indirect closed system",
            "D. Indirect, vented closed system"
        ],
        answer: "B. Indirect open spray system"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant number R-744 is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Butane",
            "B. Carbon monoxide",
            "C. Propane",
            "D. Carbon dioxide"
        ],
        answer: "D. Carbon dioxide"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant number R-1150 is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Propylene",
            "B. Ethene",
            "C. Ethane",
            "D. Methyl Formate"
        ],
        answer: "B. Ethene"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant number R-40 is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Chlorodifluoromethane",
            "B. Difluoromethane",
            "C. Ammonia",
            "D. Chloromethane"
        ],
        answer: "D. Chloromethane"
    },
    {
        question: "When the air duct system serves several enclosed spaces, the permissible quantity of refrigerant in the system shall not exceed the amount determined by using the total volume of those spaces in which the airflow cannot be reduced to less than ______ of its maximum when the fan is operating.",
        choices: [
            "A. one-quarter",
            "B. one half-quarter",
            "C. three-quarter",
            "D. one fourth-quarter"
        ],
        answer: "A. one-quarter"
    },
    {
        question: "The space above a suspended ceiling shall not be included in calculating the permissible quantity of refrigerant in the system unless such space is continuous and is part of the air return system.",
        choices: [
            "A. Partition",
            "B. Renums",
            "C. Separator",
            "D. Rate divider"
        ],
        answer: "B. Renums"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a possible location of service valve?",
        choices: [
            "A. suction of compressor",
            "B. discharge of compressor",
            "C. outlet of liquid receiver",
            "D. outlet of condenser"
        ],
        answer: "D. outlet of condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "A coil in series with evaporator that is use to prevent the liquid refrigerant entering the compressor.",
        choices: [
            "A. Accumulator",
            "B. Liquid superheater",
            "C. Drier loop",
            "D. Liquid suction heat exchanger"
        ],
        answer: "C. Drier loop"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of valve connected from discharge of compressor directly to suction that is normally closed and will open automatically only if there is high discharge pressure.",
        choices: [
            "A. check valve",
            "B. solenoid valve",
            "C. fling valve",
            "D. relief valve"
        ],
        answer: "B. solenoid valve"
    },
    {
        question: "Use to increase the capacity of condenser.",
        choices: [
            "A. water regulating valve",
            "B. desuperheating coils",
            "C. liquid-suction heat exchanger",
            "D. condenser heating coils"
        ],
        answer: "B. desuperheating coils"
    },
    {
        question: "Is use to subcooled the refrigerant from the condenser.",
        choices: [
            "A. liquid subcooler",
            "B. condenser subcooler",
            "C. desuperheating coils",
            "D. liquid receiver"
        ],
        answer: "A. liquid subcooler"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a part of low pressure side in refrigeration system?",
        choices: [
            "A. liquid line",
            "B. refrigerant flow control",
            "C. evaporator",
            "D. suction line"
        ],
        answer: "A. liquid line"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a part of high pressure side in refrigeration system?",
        choices: [
            "A. compressor",
            "B. condenser",
            "C. liquid line",
            "D. suction line"
        ],
        answer: "D. suction line"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a part of condensing unit?",
        choices: [
            "A. compressor",
            "B. discharge line",
            "C. condenser",
            "D. liquid line"
        ],
        answer: "D. liquid line"
    },
    {
        question: "By subcooling the refrigerant in refrigeration system, the compressor power per unit mass will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "Superheating the refrigerant in refrigeration system without useful cooling, the refrigeration effect per unit mass will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "By subcooling the refrigerant in refrigeration system, the specific volume at compressor suction will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "Pressure loss due to friction at the condenser, the compressor power per unit mass will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a type of air-cooled condenser?",
        choices: [
            "A. shell and tube",
            "B. natural draft",
            "C. forced draft",
            "D. induced draft"
        ],
        answer: "A. shell and tube"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of refrigerant control typically used in household refrigeration.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermostatic expansion valve",
            "B. Automatic expansion valve",
            "C. Capillary tube",
            "D. High side float"
        ],
        answer: "C. Capillary tube"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of condenser that operates like a cooling tower.",
        choices: [
            "A. air-cooled condenser",
            "B. evaporative condenser",
            "C. shell and tube condenser",
            "D. water-cooled condenser"
        ],
        answer: "B. evaporative condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "The major problem of heat pump is",
        choices: [
            "A. refrigerant used",
            "B. outside air",
            "C. supply air",
            "D. frosting"
        ],
        answer: "D. frosting"
    },
    {
        question: "Dominant refrigerant used in commercial refrigeration system.",
        choices: [
            "A. R-11",
            "B. R-22",
            "C. R-12",
            "D. R-502"
        ],
        answer: "D. R-502"
    },
    {
        question: "Cascade refrigeration system are connected in",
        choices: [
            "A. series",
            "B. parallel",
            "C. series-parallel",
            "D. parallel-series"
        ],
        answer: "A. series"
    },
    {
        question: "Is use to heat up the solution partially before entering the generator in absorption refrigeration system.",
        choices: [
            "A. rectifier",
            "B. absorber",
            "C. regenerator",
            "D. pump"
        ],
        answer: "C. regenerator"
    },
    {
        question: "The COP of actual absorption refrigeration system is usually",
        choices: [
            "A. less than 1",
            "B. less than 2",
            "C. less than 3",
            "D. less than 4"
        ],
        answer: "A. less than 1"
    },
    {
        question: "Sight glass is often located at:",
        choices: [
            "A. discharge line",
            "B. liquid line",
            "C. between condenser and liquid receiver",
            "D. suction line"
        ],
        answer: "B. liquid line"
    },
    {
        question: "Use to detects a vibration in current caused by the ionization of decomposed refrigerant between two opposite-charged platinum electrodes.",
        choices: [
            "A. Electronic detector",
            "B. Halide torch",
            "C. Rubble method",
            "D. Pressurizing"
        ],
        answer: "A. Electronic detector"
    },
    {
        question: "The ability of oil to mix with refrigerants",
        choices: [
            "A. carbonization",
            "B. purging",
            "C. mixing",
            "D. miscibility"
        ],
        answer: "D. miscibility"
    },
    {
        question: "Joints and all refrigerants-containing parts of a refrigerating system located in an air duct carrying conditioned air to and from an occupied space shall be constructed to withstand a temperature of without leakage into the airstream.",
        choices: [
            "A. 550oF",
            "B. 600oF",
            "C. 650oF",
            "D. 700oF"
        ],
        answer: "D. 700oF"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant piping crossing an open space that affords passageway in any building shall be not less than ______ above the floor unless the piping is located against the ceiling of such space and is permitted by the authority having jurisdiction.",
        choices: [
            "A. 2.2 m",
            "B. 3.2 m",
            "C. 4.2 m",
            "D. 5.2 m"
        ],
        answer: "A. 2.2 m"
    },
    {
        question: "Methyl chloride shall not be in contact with",
        choices: [
            "A. aluminum",
            "B. zinc",
            "C. magnesium",
            "D. All of these"
        ],
        answer: "D. All of these"
    },
    {
        question: "Shall not be in contact with any halogenated refrigerants.",
        choices: [
            "A. aluminum",
            "B. zinc",
            "C. magnesium",
            "D. All of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. magnesium"
    },
    {
        question: "Are suitable for use in ammonia system.",
        choices: [
            "A. copper",
            "B. aluminum and its alloy",
            "C. plastic",
            "D. cast iron"
        ],
        answer: "B. aluminum and its alloy"
    },
    {
        question: "If a pressure-relief device is used to protect a pressure vessel having an inside dimension of 6 in or less, the ultimate strength of the pressure vessel so protected shall be sufficient to withstand a pressure at least ______ the design pressure.",
        choices: [
            "A. 2 times",
            "B. 3 times",
            "C. 4 times",
            "D. 5 times"
        ],
        answer: "B. 3 times"
    },
    {
        question: "Seats and discs shall be limited in distortion, by pressure or other cause, to a set pressure change of not more than ______ in a span of five years.",
        choices: [
            "A. 1%",
            "B. 5%",
            "C. 10%",
            "D. 50%"
        ],
        answer: "B. 5%"
    },
    {
        question: "Liquid receivers, if used, or parts of a system designed to receive the refrigerant charge during pump down charges. The liquid shall not occupy more than ______ of the volume when temperature of the refrigerant is 90oF.",
        choices: [
            "A. 80%",
            "B. 85%",
            "C. 90%",
            "D. 95%"
        ],
        answer: "C. 90%"
    },
    {
        question: "The discharge line (B4) shall be vented to the atmosphere through a ______ fitted to its upper extremity.",
        choices: [
            "A. nozzle",
            "B. convergent-divergent nozzle",
            "C. pipe",
            "D. diffuser"
        ],
        answer: "D. diffuser"
    },
    {
        question: "Convert fossil fuels into shaft work.",
        choices: [
            "A. Nuclear power plant",
            "B. Gas turbine power plant",
            "C. Dendrothermal power plant",
            "D. Thermal power plant"
        ],
        answer: "D. Thermal power plant"
    },
    {
        question: "Ultimate strength drops by 30% as steam temperature raises from ______ for unalloyed steel.",
        choices: [
            "A. 300 to 400 oC",
            "B. 400 to 500 oC",
            "C. 600 to 700 oC",
            "D. 700 to 800 oC"
        ],
        answer: "B. 400 to 500 oC"
    },
    {
        question: "Recent practice limits steam temperature to",
        choices: [
            "A. 438 oC",
            "B. 538 oC",
            "C. 638 oC",
            "D. 738 oC"
        ],
        answer: "A. 438 oC"
    },
    {
        question: "In a closed feed water heater, the feed water pass through",
        choices: [
            "A. inside the tube",
            "B. outside the tube",
            "C. inside the shell",
            "D. outside the shell"
        ],
        answer: "A. inside the tube"
    },
    {
        question: "Is use if extracted steam upon condensation gets subcooled.",
        choices: [
            "A. trap",
            "B. deaerator",
            "C. filter",
            "D. drain cooler"
        ],
        answer: "D. drain cooler"
    },
    {
        question: "Needs only single pump regardless of number of heaters.",
        choices: [
            "A. open heater",
            "B. closed heater",
            "C. mono heater",
            "D. regenerative heater"
        ],
        answer: "B. closed heater"
    },
    {
        question: "Is also known as deaerator.",
        choices: [
            "A. open heater",
            "B. closed heater",
            "C. reheat heater",
            "D. regenerative heater"
        ],
        answer: "A. open heater"
    },
    {
        question: "Dissolve gases like ______ makes water corrosive react with metal to form iron oxide.",
        choices: [
            "A. O2 and N2",
            "B. O2 and CO",
            "C. O2 and CO2",
            "D. N2 and SO2"
        ],
        answer: "C. O2 and CO2"
    },
    {
        question: "A cycle typically used in paper mills, textile mills, chemical factories, sugar factories and rice mills.",
        choices: [
            "A. Cogeneration cycle",
            "B. Combined cycle",
            "C. By-product cycle",
            "D. Cascading cycle"
        ],
        answer: "A. Cogeneration cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Tranquil flow must always occur",
        choices: [
            "A. above the normal depth",
            "B. above the critical depth",
            "C. below the normal depth",
            "D. below the critical depth"
        ],
        answer: "B. above the critical depth"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of turbine employed where steam continuously extracted for process heating.",
        choices: [
            "A. Back pressure turbine",
            "B. Gas turbine",
            "C. steam turbine",
            "D. Passout turbine"
        ],
        answer: "D. Passout turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used for binary cycle power generation for high temperature application.",
        choices: [
            "A. mercury",
            "B. sodium",
            "C. potassium",
            "D. all of these"
        ],
        answer: "D. all of these"
    },
    {
        question: "Critical temperature of mercury is",
        choices: [
            "A. 1160oC",
            "B. 1260oC",
            "C. 1360oC",
            "D. 1460oC"
        ],
        answer: "D. 1460oC"
    },
    {
        question: "Critical pressure of mercury is",
        choices: [
            "A. 100 Mpa",
            "B. 108 Mpa",
            "C. 128 Mpa",
            "D. 158 Mpa"
        ],
        answer: "B. 108 Mpa"
    },
    {
        question: "Method used in converting heat directly to electricity by magnetism.",
        choices: [
            "A. Electromagnetic induction",
            "B. Magnetodynamic",
            "C. Magnetohydrodynamic",
            "D. Thermoelectric"
        ],
        answer: "C. Magnetohydrodynamic"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a material used for thermoelectric elements.",
        choices: [
            "A. Bismuth telluride",
            "B. Lead telluride",
            "C. Zinc telluride",
            "D. Germanium"
        ],
        answer: "C. Zinc telluride"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of coal formed after anthracite.",
        choices: [
            "A. Lignite",
            "B. Bituminous",
            "C. Peat",
            "D. Graphite"
        ],
        answer: "D. Graphite"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is lowest grade of coal?",
        choices: [
            "A. Peat",
            "B. Lignite",
            "C. Sub-Bituminous",
            "D. Bituminous"
        ],
        answer: "B. Lignite"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following helps in the ignition of coal?",
        choices: [
            "A. moisture",
            "B. ash",
            "C. fixed carbon",
            "D. volatile matter"
        ],
        answer: "D. volatile matter"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the ratio of fixed carbon and volatile matter.",
        choices: [
            "A. air-fuel ratio",
            "B. fuel ratio",
            "C. combustion ratio",
            "D. carbon-volatile ratio"
        ],
        answer: "B. fuel ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "A suspension of a finely divide fluid in another.",
        choices: [
            "A. filtration",
            "B. floatation",
            "C. Emulsion",
            "D. Separation"
        ],
        answer: "C. Emulsion"
    },
    {
        question: "A Contains 90% gasoline and 10% ethanol.",
        choices: [
            "A. Gasohol",
            "B. Gasonol",
            "C. Gasothanol",
            "D. Gasethanol"
        ],
        answer: "A. Gasohol"
    },
    {
        question: "Process used commercially in coal liquefaction.",
        choices: [
            "A. Tropsch process",
            "B. Fisher process",
            "C. Fisher-Tropsch process",
            "D. Mitch-Tropsch process"
        ],
        answer: "C. Fisher-Tropsch process"
    },
    {
        question: "Is an organic matter produced by plants in both land and water.",
        choices: [
            "A. Bio-ethanol",
            "B. Biomass",
            "C. Petroleum",
            "D. Biogradable"
        ],
        answer: "B. Biomass"
    },
    {
        question: "In thermal power plant, induced draft fans are located at the",
        choices: [
            "A. exit of furnace",
            "B. foot of the stack",
            "C. above the stock",
            "D. top of the stack"
        ],
        answer: "B. foot of the stack"
    },
    {
        question: "In thermal power plant, forced draft fans are installed at the",
        choices: [
            "A. foot of the stack",
            "B. top of the stack",
            "C. exit of the preheater",
            "D. inlet of the preheater"
        ],
        answer: "D. inlet of the preheater"
    },
    {
        question: "Known as drum less boiler.",
        choices: [
            "A. La Mont boilers",
            "B. Fire tube boiler",
            "C. Forced circulation boiler",
            "D. Once-through boiler"
        ],
        answer: "D. Once-through boiler"
    },
    {
        question: "Reduces the steam temperature by spraying low temperature water from boiler drum.",
        choices: [
            "A. Reheater",
            "B. Preheater",
            "C. Desuperheater",
            "D. Superheater"
        ],
        answer: "C. Desuperheater"
    },
    {
        question: "Carbon dioxide can be removed by:",
        choices: [
            "A. deaeration",
            "B. aeration",
            "C. evaporation",
            "D. vaporization"
        ],
        answer: "B. aeration"
    },
    {
        question: "A is often used to absorb silica from water.",
        choices: [
            "A. sorbent",
            "B. rectifier",
            "C. silica gel",
            "D. magnesium hydroxide"
        ],
        answer: "D. magnesium hydroxide"
    },
    {
        question: "Presence of excess hydrogen ions makes the water",
        choices: [
            "A. acidic",
            "B. alkalinity",
            "C. base",
            "D. hydroxicity"
        ],
        answer: "A. acidic"
    },
    {
        question: "PH of water varies with",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure",
            "B. temperature",
            "C. density",
            "D. volume"
        ],
        answer: "B. temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "Ph value of ______ is usually maintained for boiler water to minimized corrosion.",
        choices: [
            "A. 8.5",
            "B. 9.5",
            "C. 10.5",
            "D. 11.5"
        ],
        answer: "C. 10.5"
    },
    {
        question: "What type of turbine that has a degree of reaction of V2?",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbine",
            "B. Reaction turbine",
            "C. Rarsons turbine",
            "D. Deriaz turbine"
        ],
        answer: "C. Rarsons turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "The cooling water is made to fall in series of baffles to expose large surface area for steam fed from below to come in direct contact.",
        choices: [
            "A. Spray condenser",
            "B. Surface condenser",
            "C. Jet condenser",
            "D. Barometric condenser"
        ],
        answer: "D. Barometric condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "Show the variation of river flow (discharge) with time.",
        choices: [
            "A. Hydrograph",
            "B. Hystograph",
            "C. Mass curve",
            "D. Flow duration curve"
        ],
        answer: "A. Hydrograph"
    },
    {
        question: "Is an open channel erected on a surface above the ground.",
        choices: [
            "A. Canal",
            "B. Tunnel",
            "C. Penstock",
            "D. Flume"
        ],
        answer: "D. Flume"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of turbine used up to 300 m head.",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbine",
            "B. Francis turbine",
            "C. Propeller turbine",
            "D. Deriaz turbine"
        ],
        answer: "D. Deriaz turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "A turbine that has a diagonal flow.",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbine",
            "B. Francis turbine",
            "C. Propeller turbine",
            "D. Deriaz turbine"
        ],
        answer: "D. Deriaz turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "Oil is atomized either by air blast or pressure jet at about",
        choices: [
            "A. 60 bar",
            "B. 70 bar",
            "C. 80 bar",
            "D. 90 bar"
        ],
        answer: "B. 70 bar"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of solid injection that use single pump supplies fuel under Hqh pressure to a fuel header.",
        choices: [
            "A. Common rail injection",
            "B. Individual pump injection",
            "C. Distributor system",
            "D. Single rail injection"
        ],
        answer: "A. Common rail injection"
    },
    {
        question: "Water flow in diesel engine that is caused by density differential.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermosiphon cooling",
            "B. Thermostat cooling",
            "C. Pressurized water cooling",
            "D. Evaporative cooling"
        ],
        answer: "A. Thermosiphon cooling"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of lubrication system in diesel engine in which oil from pump is carried to a separate storage tank outside the engine cylinder and used for high capacity engine.",
        choices: [
            "A. Mist lubrication system",
            "B. Wet sump lubrication system",
            "C. Splash system",
            "D. Dry sump lubrication system"
        ],
        answer: "D. Dry sump lubrication system"
    },
    {
        question: "Produces extreme pressure differentials and violent gas vibration.",
        choices: [
            "A. Vibration",
            "B. Detonation",
            "C. Explosion",
            "D. Knocking"
        ],
        answer: "B. Detonation"
    },
    {
        question: "In a spark ignition engine, the detonation occurs near the ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. end of combustion",
            "B. middle of combustion",
            "C. beginning of combustion",
            "D. beginning of interaction"
        ],
        answer: "A. end of combustion"
    },
    {
        question: "In a compression ignition engine, the detonation occurs near the ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. end of combustion",
            "B. middle of combustion",
            "C. beginning of combustion",
            "D. beginning of interaction"
        ],
        answer: "C. beginning of combustion"
    },
    {
        question: "Morse test is use to measure the ______ of multi-cylinder engine.",
        choices: [
            "A. Brake power",
            "B. Indicated power",
            "C. Friction power",
            "D. Motor power"
        ],
        answer: "B. Indicated power"
    },
    {
        question: "Ignition delay can be minimized by adding ______ to decrease engine knocking.",
        choices: [
            "A. Ethel ether",
            "B. Ethyl chloride",
            "C. Ethyl nitrate",
            "D. Ethyl oxide"
        ],
        answer: "C. Ethyl nitrate"
    },
    {
        question: "For the submerged plane surface, the point on the surface where the resultant force acts is called the ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. Center of buoyancy",
            "B. Center of gravity",
            "C. center of pressure",
            "D. center of attraction"
        ],
        answer: "C. center of pressure"
    },
    {
        question: "At any point in fluid at rest, the pressure is the same in all directions. This principle is known as:",
        choices: [
            "A. Bernoulli Principle",
            "B. Archimedes Principle",
            "C. Pascal's Law",
            "D. Torricelli's Law"
        ],
        answer: "C. Pascal's Law"
    },
    {
        question: "The hot-wire manometer is used to measure",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure in gasses",
            "B. pressure in liquids",
            "C. wind velocities at airports",
            "D. gas velocities"
        ],
        answer: "D. gas velocities"
    },
    {
        question: "The pitot static tube measures",
        choices: [
            "A. the static pressure",
            "B. the gage pressure",
            "C. the total pressure",
            "D. the dynamic pressure"
        ],
        answer: "A. the static pressure"
    },
    {
        question: "The terminal velocity of a small sphere setting in a viscous fluid varies as the",
        choices: [
            "A. first power of its diameter",
            "B. inverse of fluid viscosity",
            "C. inverse square of the diameter",
            "D. inverse of the diameter"
        ],
        answer: "B. inverse of fluid viscosity"
    },
    {
        question: "Pressure drag results from",
        choices: [
            "A. skin friction",
            "B. deformation drag",
            "C. breakdown of potential flow near the forward stagnation point",
            "D. occurrences of wake"
        ],
        answer: "A. skin friction"
    },
    {
        question: "The pressure coefficient is the ratio of pressure forces to:",
        choices: [
            "A. viscous forces",
            "B. inertia forces",
            "C. gravity forces",
            "D. surface tension force"
        ],
        answer: "B. inertia forces"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following head loss coefficient among the following types of entrance?",
        choices: [
            "A. bell mouth",
            "B. square edge",
            "C. reentrant",
            "D. it depends"
        ],
        answer: "C. reentrant"
    },
    {
        question: "What waste water treatment method involves of algae from stabilization pond effluents?",
        choices: [
            "A. sedimentation",
            "B. floatation",
            "C. filtration",
            "D. microscreening"
        ],
        answer: "D. microscreening"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of nozzles will depend on the quantity of steam required by the turbine. If nozzles occupy the entire arc of the ring , the turbine is said to have:",
        choices: [
            "A. partially full peripheral admission",
            "B. one-half full peripheral admission",
            "C. maximum peripheral admission",
            "D. full peripheral admission"
        ],
        answer: "D. full peripheral admission"
    },
    {
        question: "Tandem compound units may also have two low-pressure castings that produces:",
        choices: [
            "A. single flow",
            "B. double flow",
            "C. triple flow",
            "D. quadruple flow"
        ],
        answer: "C. triple flow"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of turbine used for driving pumps, fans, and other auxiliaries in power plant commonly operate at exhaust pressures approximating atmospheric.",
        choices: [
            "A. Tandem compound turbine",
            "B. Passout turbine",
            "C. Cross-compound turbine",
            "D. Back pressure turbine"
        ],
        answer: "D. Back pressure turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "A governor with 0% regulation is termed as:",
        choices: [
            "A. Isochronous governor",
            "B. synchronous governor",
            "C. Isenchronous governor",
            "D. isobarrous governor"
        ],
        answer: "A. Isochronous governor"
    },
    {
        question: "The speed regulation for most turbine-generators is adjustable from:",
        choices: [
            "A. 2 to 6%",
            "B. 4 to 8%",
            "C. 6 to 10%",
            "D. 8 to 12%"
        ],
        answer: "A. 2 to 6%"
    },
    {
        question: "Poppet valves of steam turbine are used for extraction pressures of:",
        choices: [
            "A. 20 to 120 psig",
            "B. 20 to 150 psig",
            "C. 20 to 130 psig",
            "D. 20 to 140 psig"
        ],
        answer: "B. 20 to 150 psig"
    },
    {
        question: "When both bearings of steam engine are on one side of the connecting rod, the engine is referred to as:",
        choices: [
            "A. center-crank engine",
            "B. side crank engine",
            "C. under crank engine",
            "D. standard crank engine"
        ],
        answer: "B. side crank engine"
    },
    {
        question: "When the valve in steam engine is in mid-position of its travel, it will cover the steam port by an amount known as:",
        choices: [
            "A. steam lap",
            "B. partial lap",
            "C. full lap",
            "D. angular lap"
        ],
        answer: "A. steam lap"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of governor in steam engine that do not control the actual admission of steam to the cylinder, but controls the pressure of the steam.",
        choices: [
            "A. flyball governor",
            "B. variable cut-off governor",
            "C. throttling governor",
            "D. shaft governor"
        ],
        answer: "C. throttling governor"
    },
    {
        question: "By inter-cooling using two stage compressor of Brayton cycle, the backwork ratio will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "On dynamic similitude, the relation which represents the ratio of inertia force to pressure force is;",
        choices: [
            "A. Froude number",
            "B. Cauchy number",
            "C. Euler number",
            "D. Reynolds number"
        ],
        answer: "C. Euler number"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the maximum velocity in a sewer flowing full?",
        choices: [
            "A. 0.6 m/sec",
            "B. 0.9 m/sec",
            "C. 1.2 m/sec",
            "D. 1.8 m/sec"
        ],
        answer: "A. 0.6 m/sec"
    },
    {
        question: "A temporary structures constructed to exclude water from the site of the foundation during its excavation and construction is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. caisson",
            "B. retaining wall",
            "C. coffer dam",
            "D. earth dam"
        ],
        answer: "C. coffer dam"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is not a physical characteristics of water?",
        choices: [
            "A. total, suspended and dissolved solids",
            "B. tubidity",
            "C. color",
            "D. hardness"
        ],
        answer: "D. hardness"
    },
    {
        question: "Which dam is best for weak foundation?",
        choices: [
            "A. gravity",
            "B. arch",
            "C. buttress",
            "D. earth"
        ],
        answer: "C. buttress"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the volume of water which will drain freely from the aquifer?",
        choices: [
            "A. specific yield",
            "B. reservoir yield",
            "C. safe yield",
            "D. secondary yield"
        ],
        answer: "A. specific yield"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the line defined by the water level in a group of artesian wells?",
        choices: [
            "A. water table",
            "B. peizometric surface",
            "C. specific yield",
            "D. all of the above"
        ],
        answer: "B. peizometric surface"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the one that is a positive indication of pollution of a river.",
        choices: [
            "A. acidity",
            "B. oxygen content",
            "C. chloride content",
            "D. nitrite content"
        ],
        answer: "C. chloride content"
    },
    {
        question: "Which instruments is used to measure humidity of the atmosphere continuously?",
        choices: [
            "A. barograph",
            "B. thermograph",
            "C. hydrograph",
            "D. thermo-hydrograph"
        ],
        answer: "C. hydrograph"
    },
    {
        question: "Entrance losses between tank and pipe or losses through elbows, fittings and valves are generally expresses as a functions of:",
        choices: [
            "A. kinetic energy",
            "B. pipe diameter",
            "C. friction factor",
            "D. volume flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "A. kinetic energy"
    },
    {
        question: "The air that contains no water vapor is called",
        choices: [
            "A. zero air",
            "B. saturated air",
            "C. dry air",
            "D. humid air"
        ],
        answer: "C. dry air"
    },
    {
        question: "In psychrometric chart, the constant-enthalpy lines coincide with constant-temperature lines at temperature",
        choices: [
            "A. above 50oC",
            "B. below 40oC",
            "C. below 50oC",
            "D. above 10oC"
        ],
        answer: "C. below 50oC"
    },
    {
        question: "The amount of moisture in air depends on its",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure",
            "B. volume",
            "C. temperature",
            "D. humidity"
        ],
        answer: "C. temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "The deep body temperature of healthy person is maintained constant at",
        choices: [
            "A. 27oC",
            "B. 37oC",
            "C. 47oC",
            "D. 48oC"
        ],
        answer: "B. 37oC"
    },
    {
        question: "Air motion also plays important role in",
        choices: [
            "A. surroundings",
            "B. cooling",
            "C. human comfort",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. human comfort"
    },
    {
        question: "During simple heating and cooling process has a ______ humidity ratio.",
        choices: [
            "A. increasing",
            "B. decreasing",
            "C. constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. constant"
    },
    {
        question: "The ______ follows a line of constant wet-bub temperature on the psychrometric chart.",
        choices: [
            "A. evaporative cooling process",
            "B. condensive cooling process",
            "C. direct cooling process",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. evaporative cooling process"
    },
    {
        question: "A vapor which is not about to condense is called a",
        choices: [
            "A. mixture of vapor and liquid",
            "B. critical vapor",
            "C. superheated vapor",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. superheated vapor"
    },
    {
        question: "Passing from the solid phase directly into vapor phase is called",
        choices: [
            "A. condensation",
            "B. fusion",
            "C. sublimation",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. sublimation"
    },
    {
        question: "Robert Boyle observed during his experiments with a vacuum chamber that the pressure of gases is inversely proportional to their",
        choices: [
            "A. temperature",
            "B. pressure",
            "C. volume",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. volume"
    },
    {
        question: "______ is energy in transition.",
        choices: [
            "A. heat",
            "B. work",
            "C. power",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. heat"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the mode of energy transfer between a solid surface and the adjacent liquid or gas which is in motion, and it involves combine effects of conduction and fluid motion.",
        choices: [
            "A. conduction",
            "B. convection",
            "C. radiation",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. convection"
    },
    {
        question: "Radiation is usually considered as",
        choices: [
            "A. surface phenomenon",
            "B. surface interaction",
            "C. surface corrosion",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. surface phenomenon"
    },
    {
        question: "Work is ______ between the system and the surroundings.",
        choices: [
            "A. work interaction",
            "B. energy interaction",
            "C. heat interaction",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. energy interaction"
    },
    {
        question: "Is a process during which the system remains in equilibrium at all times.",
        choices: [
            "A. Quasi-equilibrium",
            "B. static equilibrium",
            "C. dynamic equilibrium",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. Quasi-equilibrium"
    },
    {
        question: "In the absence of any work interactions between a system and its surroundings, the amount of net heat transfer is equal",
        choices: [
            "A. to the change in the total energy of a closed system.",
            "B. to heat and work",
            "C. energy interactions",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. to the change in the total energy of a closed system."
    },
    {
        question: "The constant volume and constant pressure specific heats are identical for",
        choices: [
            "A. compressible substance",
            "B. incompressible substance",
            "C. compressible gas",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. incompressible substance"
    },
    {
        question: "The velocity of fluid is zero at the wall and maximum at the center because of the",
        choices: [
            "A. velocity effect",
            "B. viscous effect",
            "C. temperature effect",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. viscous effect"
    },
    {
        question: "For steady flow devices, the volume of the control volume is",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. constant"
    },
    {
        question: "The work done in a turbine is ______ since it is done by the fluid.",
        choices: [
            "A. positive",
            "B. negative",
            "C. zero",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. positive"
    },
    {
        question: "Reheating process in Brayton cycle, the turbine work will",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of the these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the chemical formula of Ethanol?",
        choices: [
            "A. C7H16",
            "B. C2H6O",
            "C. C7H8",
            "D. C6H12"
        ],
        answer: "B. C2H6O"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the chemical formula of Heptane?",
        choices: [
            "A. C7H16",
            "B. C2H6O",
            "C. C7H8",
            "D. C6H12"
        ],
        answer: "A. C7H16"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the chemical formula of Hexene?",
        choices: [
            "A. C7H16",
            "B. C2H6O",
            "C. C7H8",
            "D. C6H12"
        ],
        answer: "D. C6H12"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the chemical formula of Toluene?",
        choices: [
            "A. C7H16",
            "B. C2H6O",
            "C. C7H8",
            "D. C6H12"
        ],
        answer: "C. C7H8"
    },
    {
        question: "As the air passes through a nozzle, which of the following will increase?",
        choices: [
            "A. temperature",
            "B. enthalpy",
            "C. internal energy",
            "D. mach number"
        ],
        answer: "D. mach number"
    },
    {
        question: "As the air passes through a diffuser, which of the following will decrease?",
        choices: [
            "A. temperature",
            "B. enthalpy",
            "C. internal energy",
            "D. mach number"
        ],
        answer: "D. mach number"
    },
    {
        question: "As the air passes through a nozzle, which of the following will decrease?",
        choices: [
            "A. entropy",
            "B. velocity",
            "C. internal energy",
            "D. mach number"
        ],
        answer: "C. internal energy"
    },
    {
        question: "As the air passes through a diffuser, which of the following will increase?",
        choices: [
            "A. density",
            "B. entropy",
            "C. mach number",
            "D. velocity"
        ],
        answer: "A. density"
    },
    {
        question: "After passing through a convergent-divergent nozzle, the temperature of air will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "After passing through a convergent-divergent nozzle, the density of air will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "After passing through a convergent-divergent nozzle, the mach number of air will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the temperature source of Carnot cycle, which of the following will not be affected?",
        choices: [
            "A. efficiency",
            "B. work",
            "C. heat added",
            "D. heat rejected"
        ],
        answer: "D. heat rejected"
    },
    {
        question: "By decreasing the temperature sink of Carnot cycle, which of the following will not be affected?",
        choices: [
            "A. efficiency",
            "B. work",
            "C. heat added",
            "D. heat rejected"
        ],
        answer: "C. heat added"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle with useful cooling, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. condenser pressure",
            "B. evaporator pressure",
            "C. quality after expansion",
            "D. heat rejected from condenser"
        ],
        answer: "D. heat rejected from condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle with useful cooling, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. COP",
            "C. Compressor power",
            "D. Mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "D. Mass flow rate"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle without useful cooling, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat rejected",
            "B. COP",
            "C. Compressor power",
            "D. specific volume at suction"
        ],
        answer: "B. COP"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle without useful cooling, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. COP",
            "C. Compressor power",
            "D. mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "C. Compressor power"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle without useful cooling, which of the following will not be affected? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. COP",
            "C. Compressor power",
            "D. mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "C. Compressor power"
    },
    {
        question: "By sub-cooling the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle at condenser exit, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. Specific volume at suction",
            "C. Compressor power",
            "D. mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "A. Refrigerating effect"
    },
    {
        question: "By sub-cooling the refrigerant in vapor compression cycle at condenser exit, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Coefficient of performance",
            "B. Heat rejected from condenser",
            "C. Refrigerating effect",
            "D. mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "D. mass flow rate"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the vaporizing temperature in vapor compression cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. mass flow rate",
            "B. COP",
            "C. specific volume at suction",
            "D. compressor work"
        ],
        answer: "B. COP"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the vaporizing temperature in vapor compression cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. COP",
            "C. evaporator temperature",
            "D. temperature difference between evaporator and compressor"
        ],
        answer: "D. temperature difference between evaporator and compressor"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the condenser pressure in vapor compression cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. COP",
            "C. Specific volume at suction",
            "D. Compressor power"
        ],
        answer: "D. Compressor power"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the condenser pressure in vapor compression cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. moisture content after expansion",
            "B. compressor power",
            "C. heat rejected from condenser",
            "D. mass flow rate"
        ],
        answer: "A. moisture content after expansion"
    },
    {
        question: "If the pressure drop in the condenser increases in a vapor compression cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. mass flow rate",
            "B. compressor power",
            "C. heat rejected in the condenser",
            "D. specific volume at suction"
        ],
        answer: "C. heat rejected in the condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "If the pressure drop in the condenser increases in a vapor compression cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. mass flow rate",
            "C. heat rejected in the condenser",
            "D. Compressor power"
        ],
        answer: "B. mass flow rate"
    },
    {
        question: "If the pressure drop in the condenser increases in a vapor compression cycle, which of the following will not be affected? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. compressor power",
            "B. mass flow rate",
            "C. heat rejected in the condenser",
            "D. COP"
        ],
        answer: "A. compressor power"
    },
    {
        question: "If the pressure drop in the evaporator increases in a vapor compression cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerating effect",
            "B. vaporizing temperature",
            "C. heat rejected in the condenser",
            "D. COP"
        ],
        answer: "C. heat rejected in the condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "If the pressure drop in the evaporator increases in a vapor compression cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. specific volume at suction",
            "B. compressor power",
            "C. heat rejected in the condenser",
            "D. COP"
        ],
        answer: "D. COP"
    },
    {
        question: "By lowering the condenser pressure in Rankine cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. pump work",
            "B. turbine work",
            "C. heat rejected",
            "D. cycle efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "C. heat rejected"
    },
    {
        question: "By increasing the boiler pressure in Rankine cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. heat rejected",
            "B. pump work",
            "C. cycle efficiency",
            "D. moisture content"
        ],
        answer: "A. heat rejected"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the steam to a higher temperature in Rankine cycle, which of the following will decrease? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. moisture content at the turbine exhaust",
            "B. turbine work",
            "C. heat added",
            "D. heat rejected"
        ],
        answer: "A. moisture content at the turbine exhaust"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the steam to a higher temperature in Rankine cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. moisture content at the turbine exhaust",
            "B. pump work",
            "C. condenser pressure",
            "D. cycle efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "D. cycle efficiency"
    },
    {
        question: "By superheating the steam to a higher temperature in Rankine cycle, which of the following will increase? (Use per unit mass analysis)",
        choices: [
            "A. moisture content at the turbine exhaust",
            "B. pump work",
            "C. condenser pressure",
            "D. cycle efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "B. pump work"
    },
    {
        question: "By reheating the steam before entering the second stage in Rankine cycle, which of the following will decrease?",
        choices: [
            "A. turbine work",
            "B. moisture content after expansion",
            "C. heat added",
            "D. heat rejected"
        ],
        answer: "B. moisture content after expansion"
    },
    {
        question: "When Rankine cycle is modified with regeneration, which of the following will increase?",
        choices: [
            "A. turbine work",
            "B. heat added",
            "C. heat rejected",
            "D. cycle efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "D. cycle efficiency"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the combination of base load and peaking load.",
        choices: [
            "A. rated load",
            "B. intermediate load",
            "C. combine load",
            "D. over-all load"
        ],
        answer: "B. intermediate load"
    },
    {
        question: "Sum of the maximum demand over the simultaneous maximum demand.",
        choices: [
            "A. Use factor",
            "B. capacity factor",
            "C. demand factor",
            "D. diversity factor"
        ],
        answer: "D. diversity factor"
    },
    {
        question: "Regenerative with feed heating cycle with infinite number of feedwater heaters thus efficiency is equal to:",
        choices: [
            "A. Otto cycle",
            "B. Stirling cycle",
            "C. Ericson cycle",
            "D. Carnot cycle"
        ],
        answer: "D. Carnot cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of turbine used in desalination of sea water.",
        choices: [
            "A. Back pressure turbine",
            "B. Passout turbine",
            "C. Peaking turbine",
            "D. Reaction turbine"
        ],
        answer: "A. Back pressure turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "States that when conductor and a magnetic field move relatively to each other, an electric voltage is induced in the conductor.",
        choices: [
            "A. Maxwell's law",
            "B. Kirchoff's law",
            "C. Faraday's law",
            "D. Newton's law"
        ],
        answer: "C. Faraday's law"
    },
    {
        question: "Transfers heat directly to electrical energy by utilizing thermionic emissions.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermionic motor",
            "B. Thermionic generator",
            "C. Thermionic converter",
            "D. Thermionic cell"
        ],
        answer: "B. Thermionic generator"
    },
    {
        question: "Is the largest group of coal containing 46-86% of fixed carbon and 20 to 40% volatile matter.",
        choices: [
            "A. Anthracite",
            "B. Sub-anthracite",
            "C. Bituminous",
            "D. Sub-bituminous"
        ],
        answer: "C. Bituminous"
    },
    {
        question: "When 1 gram of coal is subjected to a temperature of about 105 oC for a period of 1 hour, the loss in weight of the sample gives the:",
        choices: [
            "A. volatile matter",
            "B. ash",
            "C. Fixed carbon",
            "D. moisture content"
        ],
        answer: "D. moisture content"
    },
    {
        question: "When 1 gram of sample of coal is placed in a crucible and heated 950 oC and maintain at that temperature for 7 minutes there is a loss in weight due to elimination of:",
        choices: [
            "A. volatile matter and moisture",
            "B. salt",
            "C. Fixed carbon",
            "D. moisture content"
        ],
        answer: "A. volatile matter and moisture"
    },
    {
        question: "As the air passes through a diffuser, which of the following will increase?",
        choices: [
            "A. density",
            "B. entropy",
            "C. mach number",
            "D. velocity"
        ],
        answer: "A. density"
    },
    {
        question: "Consist of hydrogen and certain hydrogen carbon compounds which can be removed from coal by heating.",
        choices: [
            "A. Moisture content",
            "B. Product of combustion",
            "C. Ash",
            "D. volatile matter"
        ],
        answer: "D. volatile matter"
    },
    {
        question: "By heating 1 gram of coal in an uncovered crucible until the coal is completely burned, the ______ will formed.",
        choices: [
            "A. volatile matter and moisture",
            "B. ash",
            "C. Fixed carbon",
            "D. moisture content"
        ],
        answer: "B. ash"
    },
    {
        question: "Caking coal are used to produce coke by heating in a coke oven in the absence of ______ with volatile matter driven off.",
        choices: [
            "A. air",
            "B. oil",
            "C. Oxygen",
            "D. Nitrogen"
        ],
        answer: "A. air"
    },
    {
        question: "Gndability of standard coal is:",
        choices: [
            "A. 80",
            "B. 90",
            "C. 100",
            "D. 110"
        ],
        answer: "C. 100"
    },
    {
        question: "Major constituent of all natural gases is:",
        choices: [
            "A. ethane",
            "B. methane",
            "C. propane",
            "D. Cathane"
        ],
        answer: "B. methane"
    },
    {
        question: "Two types of fans are:",
        choices: [
            "A. centrifugal and axial",
            "B. reciprocating and axial",
            "C. centrifugal and rotary",
            "D. tangential and rotary"
        ],
        answer: "A. centrifugal and axial"
    },
    {
        question: "Enthalpy of substance at specified state due to chemical composition.",
        choices: [
            "A. Enthalpy of reaction",
            "B. Enthalpy of combustion",
            "C. Enthalpy of formation",
            "D. Enthalpy of product"
        ],
        answer: "C. Enthalpy of formation"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of boiler used for super critical pressure operation.",
        choices: [
            "A. La Mont boiler",
            "B. Once-through-drculation boiler",
            "C. Force circulation boiler",
            "D. Natural circulation boiler"
        ],
        answer: "B. Once-through-drculation boiler"
    },
    {
        question: "Economizer in a water tube boiler is heated by:",
        choices: [
            "A. electric furnace",
            "B. electric current",
            "C. incoming flue gas",
            "D. outgoing flue gas"
        ],
        answer: "D. outgoing flue gas"
    },
    {
        question: "Receives heat partly by convection and partly by radiation.",
        choices: [
            "A. radiant superheater",
            "B. desuperheater",
            "C. convective superheater",
            "D. pendant superheater"
        ],
        answer: "D. pendant superheater"
    },
    {
        question: "Regenerative superheater is a storage type of heat exchangers have an energy storage medium called:",
        choices: [
            "A. Matrix",
            "B. Regenerator",
            "C. Boiler",
            "D. Recuperator"
        ],
        answer: "A. Matrix"
    },
    {
        question: "Stirling cycle uses a ______ as working fluids.",
        choices: [
            "A. incompressible gas",
            "B. incompressible fluids",
            "C. compressible refrigerant",
            "D. compressible fluids"
        ],
        answer: "D. compressible fluids"
    },
    {
        question: "In Stirling process the heat is added during",
        choices: [
            "A. isobaric process",
            "B. isentropic process",
            "C. isothermal process",
            "D. heat process"
        ],
        answer: "C. isothermal process"
    },
    {
        question: "Brayton cycle is also known as",
        choices: [
            "A. Carnot cycle",
            "B. Joule cycle",
            "C. Diesel cycle",
            "D. Rankine cycle"
        ],
        answer: "B. Joule cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Is applied to propulsion of vehicles because of certain practical characteristics.",
        choices: [
            "A. Diesel cycle",
            "B. Otto cycle",
            "C. Carnot cycle",
            "D. Brayton cycle"
        ],
        answer: "D. Brayton cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Heat exchangers typically involve",
        choices: [
            "A. no work interactions",
            "B. no heat interactions",
            "C. no energy interactions",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. no work interactions"
    },
    {
        question: "A device that is used to convert the heat to work is called",
        choices: [
            "A. adiabatic",
            "B. regenerator",
            "C. heat engines",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. heat engines"
    },
    {
        question: "The objective of a heat pump is to maintain a heated space at",
        choices: [
            "A. low temperature",
            "B. high temperature",
            "C. medium temperature",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. high temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "A device that violates the second law of thermodynamics is called",
        choices: [
            "A. perpetual motion machine of second kind",
            "B. perpetual motion machine of third kind",
            "C. perpetual-motion machine of the first kind",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. perpetual motion machine of second kind"
    },
    {
        question: "A process is called ______ if no irreversibilities occur outside the system boundaries during the process.",
        choices: [
            "A. externally reversible",
            "B. internally reversible",
            "C. reversible",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. reversible"
    },
    {
        question: "An energy interaction which is not accompanied by entropy transfer is",
        choices: [
            "A. energy",
            "B. heat",
            "C. work",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. work"
    },
    {
        question: "A ______ is used in aircraft engines and some automotive engine. In this method, a turbine driven by the exhaust gases is used to provide power to compressor or blower at the inlet.",
        choices: [
            "A. discharging",
            "B. turbocharging",
            "C. supercharging",
            "D. scavenging"
        ],
        answer: "B. turbocharging"
    },
    {
        question: "The only devices where the changes in kinetic energy are significant are the",
        choices: [
            "A. compressor",
            "B. pumps",
            "C. nozzles and diffusers",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. nozzles and diffusers"
    },
    {
        question: "The distance between TDC and BDC in which the piston can travel is the",
        choices: [
            "A. right extreme position",
            "B. displacement stroke",
            "C. stroke of the engine",
            "D. swept stroke"
        ],
        answer: "C. stroke of the engine"
    },
    {
        question: "In compression-engine, the combustion of air-fuel mixture is self-ignited as a result of compressing the mixture above its",
        choices: [
            "A. self developed temperature",
            "B. mixing temperature",
            "C. self feed temperature",
            "D. self ignition temperature"
        ],
        answer: "D. self ignition temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "The thermal efficiency of an ideal Otto cycle depends ______ of the working fluid.",
        choices: [
            "A. the pressure ratio of the engine and the specific heat ratio",
            "B. the temperature ratio of the engine and the specific heat ratio",
            "C. the moles ratio of the engine and the specific heat ratio",
            "D. the compression ratio of the engine and the specific heat ratio"
        ],
        answer: "D. the compression ratio of the engine and the specific heat ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "Using monatomic gas, the thermal efficiency of Otto cycle",
        choices: [
            "A. increases",
            "B. decreases",
            "C. remains constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increases"
    },
    {
        question: "In diesel engine, combustion process during combustion occurs during",
        choices: [
            "A. isothermal process",
            "B. constant pressure process",
            "C. isentropic process",
            "D. adiabatic"
        ],
        answer: "B. constant pressure process"
    },
    {
        question: "If the cutoff ratio decreases, the efficiency of diesel cycle",
        choices: [
            "A. increases",
            "B. decreases",
            "C. remains constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increases"
    },
    {
        question: "In Ericsson cycle, the regeneration process occur during ______ process.",
        choices: [
            "A. constant volume",
            "B. constant temperature",
            "C. constant pressure",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. constant pressure"
    },
    {
        question: "In Brayton cycle, the ______ during constant pressure process.",
        choices: [
            "A. work is added",
            "B. heat is transferred",
            "C. pressure is rejected",
            "D. energy is added"
        ],
        answer: "B. heat is transferred"
    },
    {
        question: "The two major application areas of gas turbine engines are",
        choices: [
            "A. driving automotive engine and locomotives",
            "B. heating and generation",
            "C. aircraft propulsion and electric power generation",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. aircraft propulsion and electric power generation"
    },
    {
        question: "The use of regenerator in is recommended only when the turbine exhaust temperature is higher than the compressor",
        choices: [
            "A. exit temperature",
            "B. inlet temperature",
            "C. mean temperature",
            "D. absolute temperature"
        ],
        answer: "A. exit temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "As the number of stages is increased, the expansion process becomes",
        choices: [
            "A. isentropic",
            "B. isothermal",
            "C. isometric",
            "D. polytropic"
        ],
        answer: "B. isothermal"
    },
    {
        question: "Aircraft gas turbines operate at higher pressure ratio typically between",
        choices: [
            "A. 6 to 8",
            "B. 12 to 24",
            "C. 10 to 18",
            "D. 10 to 25"
        ],
        answer: "D. 10 to 25"
    },
    {
        question: "The first commercial high- pass ratio engines has a bypass ratio of",
        choices: [
            "A. 1",
            "B. 3",
            "C. 5",
            "D. 7"
        ],
        answer: "C. 5"
    },
    {
        question: "The single-stage expansion process of an ideal Brayton cycle without regeneration is replaced by a multistage expansion process with reheating between the same pressure limits. As a result of modification, thermal efficiency will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remain constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is/are the application of Brayton cycle",
        choices: [
            "A. Propulsion system",
            "B. Automotive Turbine Engines",
            "C. Aircraft Turbine engines",
            "D. all of these"
        ],
        answer: "D. all of these"
    },
    {
        question: "It used as working fluid in high-temperature applications of vapor cycles.",
        choices: [
            "A. Helium",
            "B. Deuterium",
            "C. Mercury",
            "D. water"
        ],
        answer: "C. Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "The superheated vapor enters the turbine and expands isentropically and produces work by the rotating shaft. The ______ may drop during the process.",
        choices: [
            "A. density",
            "B. viscosity of fuel",
            "C. temperature and pressure",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. temperature and pressure"
    },
    {
        question: "Only ______ of the turbine work output is required to operate the pump.",
        choices: [
            "A. 0.01%",
            "B. 0.02%",
            "C. 0.03%",
            "D. 0.04%"
        ],
        answer: "D. 0.04%"
    },
    {
        question: "Superheating the steam to higher temperatures decreases the moisture content of the steam at the ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. turbine inlet",
            "B. compressor inlet",
            "C. compressor exit",
            "D. turbine exit"
        ],
        answer: "D. turbine exit"
    },
    {
        question: "Regeneration also provides a convenient means of derarting the feedwater to prevent",
        choices: [
            "A. boiler explosion",
            "B. boiler scale production",
            "C. boiler corrosion",
            "D. compressor damage"
        ],
        answer: "C. boiler corrosion"
    },
    {
        question: "Can be apply in Steam turbine cycle (Rankine), Gas turbine cycle (Brayton) and Combined cycle.",
        choices: [
            "A. Hydroelectric plant",
            "B. Nuclear power plant",
            "C. Cogeneration plant",
            "D. Tidal power plant"
        ],
        answer: "C. Cogeneration plant"
    },
    {
        question: "In a Rankine cycle with fixed turbine inlet conditions. What is the effect of lowering the condenser pressure, the heat rejected will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "In an ideal Rankine cycle with fixed boiler and condenser pressures. What is the effect of superheating the steam to a higher temperature, the pump work input will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains the same"
    },
    {
        question: "How do the following quantities change when the simple ideal Rankine cycle is modified with regeneration? The heat rejected will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increase",
            "B. decrease",
            "C. remains the same",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "B. decrease"
    },
    {
        question: "During a combustion process, the components which exist before the reaction are called",
        choices: [
            "A. reaction",
            "B. combustion",
            "C. reactants",
            "D. product"
        ],
        answer: "C. reactants"
    },
    {
        question: "Is an obvious reason for incomplete combustion.",
        choices: [
            "A. Insufficient carbon",
            "B. Insufficient air",
            "C. Insufficient nitrogen",
            "D. Insufficient oxygen"
        ],
        answer: "D. Insufficient oxygen"
    },
    {
        question: "Higher heating value when H2O in the product of combustion is in",
        choices: [
            "A. solid form",
            "B. vapor form",
            "C. gas form",
            "D. liquid form"
        ],
        answer: "D. liquid form"
    },
    {
        question: "Device which transfer heat from low temperature medium to a high temperature one is a",
        choices: [
            "A. adiabatic",
            "B. refrigerator",
            "C. heat exchanger",
            "D. heat pump"
        ],
        answer: "D. heat pump"
    },
    {
        question: "A rule of thumb is that the COP improves by ______ for each OC the evaporating temperature is raised or the condensing temperature is lowered.",
        choices: [
            "A. 2 to 4%",
            "B. 6 to 7%",
            "C. 1 to 5%",
            "D. 6 to 10%"
        ],
        answer: "A. 2 to 4%"
    },
    {
        question: "Are generally more expensive to purchase and install than other heating systems, but they save money in the long run.",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerator",
            "B. Adiabator",
            "C. Heat pumps",
            "D. humidifier"
        ],
        answer: "C. Heat pumps"
    },
    {
        question: "The work done in throttling valve is",
        choices: [
            "A. zero",
            "B. one",
            "C. infinity",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. zero"
    },
    {
        question: "Stagnation enthalpy represents the enthalpy of a fluid when it is brought to rest ______.",
        choices: [
            "A. diabatically",
            "B. adiabatically",
            "C. isothermally",
            "D. isobarically"
        ],
        answer: "B. adiabatically"
    },
    {
        question: "Represents the temperature an ideal gas will attain when it is brought to rest adiabatically.",
        choices: [
            "A. absolute zero temperature",
            "B. stagnation temperature",
            "C. boiling temperature",
            "D. critical temperature"
        ],
        answer: "B. stagnation temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "After passing through a nozzle the density of fluid decreases as the fluid velocity",
        choices: [
            "A. increases",
            "B. decreases",
            "C. remains constant",
            "D. none of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. increases"
    },
    {
        question: "The volume flow passes through a venturi meter will:",
        choices: [
            "A. increases",
            "B. decreases",
            "C. constant",
            "D. varying"
        ],
        answer: "C. constant"
    },
    {
        question: "A converging-diverging nozzle is the standard equipment in",
        choices: [
            "A. subsonic aircraft",
            "B. supersonic aircraft",
            "C. hypersonic aircraft",
            "D. trisonic aircraft"
        ],
        answer: "B. supersonic aircraft"
    },
    {
        question: "Nozzle efficiencies range from",
        choices: [
            "A. 78 to 89%",
            "B. 80 to 90%",
            "C. 90 to 99%",
            "D. 93 to 98%"
        ],
        answer: "C. 90 to 99%"
    },
    {
        question: "By reheating the steam before entering the second stage in Rankine cycle, which of the following will increase?",
        choices: [
            "A. pump work",
            "B. Heat rejected",
            "C. moisture content after expansion",
            "D. condenser pressure"
        ],
        answer: "B. Heat rejected"
    },
    {
        question: "A type of condenser combines the functions of a condenser and cooling tower is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. air-cooled condenser",
            "B. water-cooled condenser",
            "C. ground-cooling condenser",
            "D. evaporative condenser"
        ],
        answer: "D. evaporative condenser"
    },
    {
        question: "An expansion valve with a fluid-charged remote bulb that maintains a constant degree of superheat in the evaporator is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. thermostatic expansion valve",
            "B. capillary tube",
            "C. automatic expansion valve",
            "D. float valve"
        ],
        answer: "A. thermostatic expansion valve"
    },
    {
        question: "A refrigeration system ideally suited for use in air-craft because it is light in weight and requires less space is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. mechanical vapor-compression",
            "B. steam-jet",
            "C. air cycle",
            "D. vapor absorption"
        ],
        answer: "C. air cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant with chemical formula CHClF2 is designated by:",
        choices: [
            "A. R134a",
            "B. R11",
            "C. R12",
            "D. R22"
        ],
        answer: "D. R22"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant with chemical formula CF3CH2F is designated by:",
        choices: [
            "A. R134a",
            "B. R11",
            "C. R12",
            "D. R22"
        ],
        answer: "A. R134a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which refrigerant does not belong to the group?",
        choices: [
            "A. ammonia",
            "B. methane",
            "C. propane",
            "D. Isobutane"
        ],
        answer: "A. ammonia"
    },
    {
        question: "Carbon dioxide refrigerant is designated by:",
        choices: [
            "A. R717",
            "B. R600",
            "C. R714",
            "D. R 718"
        ],
        answer: "C. R714"
    },
    {
        question: "Piping, fittings and valves materials found suitable for use in ammonia refrigerant are manufactured from:",
        choices: [
            "A. Copper",
            "B. Iron and Steel",
            "C. Aluminum",
            "D. Brass"
        ],
        answer: "B. Iron and Steel"
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement is correct with water-cooled shell and tube type of condenser?",
        choices: [
            "A. Refrigerant condensing inside tubes and water flowing in the shell.",
            "B. Water flowing through passes inside tubes and the refrigerator condensing in the shell.",
            "C. Both refrigerant and water flowing through passes inside tubes and refrigerant condensing.",
            "D. A, B, and C are correct"
        ],
        answer: "B. Water flowing through passes inside tubes and the refrigerator condensing in the shell."
    },
    {
        question: "In a vapour-absorption refrigeration system utilizing ammonia as refrigerant and the absorbent is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Water",
            "B. Lithium Bromide",
            "C. Carbon dioxide",
            "D. Air"
        ],
        answer: "A. Water"
    },
    {
        question: "The most common secondary refrigerant medium used in indirect refrigeration system such as in industrial ice plants and cold storages.",
        choices: [
            "A. Hydrocarbon",
            "B. Air",
            "C. Carbon dioxide",
            "D. Brine"
        ],
        answer: "D. Brine"
    },
    {
        question: "A constant restriction expansion device in refrigeration system which is merely a long tube with narrow bore is called.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermostatic expansion valve",
            "B. Capillary tube",
            "C. Automatic expansion valve",
            "D. Float valve"
        ],
        answer: "B. Capillary tube"
    },
    {
        question: "Mixtures of refrigerants but which behave like pure substance are called:",
        choices: [
            "A. Isomers",
            "B. azectropes",
            "C. hydrocarbons",
            "D. CFC"
        ],
        answer: "B. azectropes"
    },
    {
        question: "In refrigeration compressor that has an electric motor and a compressor built into an integral housing is commonly called:",
        choices: [
            "A. hermetic compressor",
            "B. combined compressor",
            "C. Open type compressor",
            "D. packaged compressor"
        ],
        answer: "A. hermetic compressor"
    },
    {
        question: "Compounds with same chemical formula but different molecular structure (such R134 & R134a) are called:",
        choices: [
            "A. brominated",
            "B. azectropes",
            "C. hydrocarbons",
            "D. Isomers"
        ],
        answer: "D. Isomers"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following refrigerants does not belong to the group:",
        choices: [
            "A. Carbon dioxide",
            "B. Water",
            "C. Ammonia",
            "D. Isobutane"
        ],
        answer: "D. Isobutane"
    },
    {
        question: "An expansion valve used for a flooded type of evaporator in a refrigeration system is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. thermostatic expansion valve",
            "B. capillary tube",
            "C. automatic expansion valve",
            "D. float valve"
        ],
        answer: "D. float valve"
    },
    {
        question: "An atom in the refrigerant molecule considered responsible for the depletion ozone layer in upper atmosphere (stratosphere)",
        choices: [
            "A. Cl atom",
            "B. F-atom",
            "C. H atom/s",
            "D. C atom"
        ],
        answer: "A. Cl atom"
    },
    {
        question: "A vapour compression system used for production of low temperatures in which a series of refrigerants, with progressively lower boiling points, are used in series of single-stage units is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. multiple-escape system",
            "B. single-stage system",
            "C. cascade system",
            "D. series system"
        ],
        answer: "C. cascade system"
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement is correct on the effect of liquid subcooling in a vapor compression system?",
        choices: [
            "A. subcooling both increases flashing of the liquid during expansion and the refrigerating effect.",
            "B. subcooling increases flashing of the liquid during expansion and increases the refrigerating effect.",
            "C. subcooling both decreases flashing of the liquid during expansion and the refrigerating effect.",
            "D. subcooling decreases flashing of the liquid during expansion and increases the refrigerating effect."
        ],
        answer: "D. subcooling decreases flashing of the liquid during expansion and increases the refrigerating effect."
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement is correct on the effect of suction vapor superheating in a vapor compression system?",
        choices: [
            "A. superheating both increases specific compressed work and the refrigerating effect.",
            "B. superheating both decrease specific compressed work and the refrigerating effect.",
            "C. superheating increases specific compressed work and decreases the refrigerating effect.",
            "D. superheating decrease specific compressed work and increases the refrigerating effect."
        ],
        answer: "A. superheating both increases specific compressed work and the refrigerating effect."
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement is correct on the effect of increasing condensing pressure in a vapor compression system?",
        choices: [
            "A. increasing condensing pressure both increases specific compressed work and the refrigerating effect.",
            "B. increasing condensing pressure both decrease specific compressed work and the refrigerating effect.",
            "C. increasing condensing pressure increases specific compressed work and decreases the refrigerating effect.",
            "D. increasing condensing pressure decrease specific compressed work and increases the refrigerating effect."
        ],
        answer: "C. increasing condensing pressure increases specific compressed work and decreases the refrigerating effect."
    },
    {
        question: "Freezing method utilizes the combined effects of low temperature and high air velocity to produce a high rate of heat transfer from product is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. indirect contact freezing",
            "B. blast freezing",
            "C. immersion freezing",
            "D. spray freezing"
        ],
        answer: "B. blast freezing"
    },
    {
        question: "A component installed a refrigeration system to ensure that no liquid enters the compressor and subcooled the liquid from condenser to prevent bubbles of vapor from impending the flow of refrigerant through expansion valve is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. liquid-to-suction heat exchanger",
            "B. flash chamber",
            "C. subcooler",
            "D. drier"
        ],
        answer: "A. liquid-to-suction heat exchanger"
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerant used in steam-jet refrigeration is:",
        choices: [
            "A. ammonia",
            "B. water",
            "C. carbon dioxide",
            "D. air"
        ],
        answer: "B. water"
    },
    {
        question: "Which refrigerant is completely miscible with oil:",
        choices: [
            "A. ammonia",
            "B. R12",
            "C. carbon dioxide",
            "D. R134a"
        ],
        answer: "B. R12"
    },
    {
        question: "Ammonia is not used in domestic refrigeration and comfort air-conditioning because:",
        choices: [
            "A. ammonia is highly soluble in water.",
            "B. ammonia is the cheapest refrigerant.",
            "C. ammonia is flammable and toxic.",
            "D. ammonia is non ozone depletion potential"
        ],
        answer: "C. ammonia is flammable and toxic."
    },
    {
        question: "Refrigerants 22 (R22) which is an HCFC, has 1/20th the ozone depletion potential (ODP) of R11 and R12. Hence, it can be continue to be used for quite sometime. However, all these have global warming-potential (GWP). Because of this, R22 will have to be phased out by year:",
        choices: [
            "A. 2010 AD",
            "B. 2030 AD",
            "C. 2020",
            "D. 2040"
        ],
        answer: "B. 2030 AD"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the statements is incorrect regarding the functions of the liquid receiver?",
        choices: [
            "A. stores unused refrigerant returning from condenser",
            "B. stores refrigerant to be evaporated by the expansion valve",
            "C. provides a place to store refrigerant when pumping out the evaporator during maintenance operations.",
            "D. stores oil that is carried along with refrigerant."
        ],
        answer: "D. stores oil that is carried along with refrigerant."
    },
    {
        question: "A shutoff valve that is actuated by an electromagnetic coil is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. solenoid valve",
            "B. float switch",
            "C. float valves",
            "D. holdback valve"
        ],
        answer: "A. solenoid valve"
    },
    {
        question: "A very important consequence of the ideal gas model is that the internal energy of an ideal gas is a function of ______ only.",
        choices: [
            "A. Pressure",
            "B. Temperature",
            "C. Point function",
            "D. Volume"
        ],
        answer: "B. Temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "At what temperature readings do the Fahrenheit and Celsius scales have the same value?",
        choices: [
            "A. ~35 degrees",
            "B. ~40 degrees",
            "C. ~45 degrees",
            "D. ~30 degrees"
        ],
        answer: "B. ~40 degrees"
    },
    {
        question: "States that if the temperature of a given quantity of gas is held constant, the volume of the gas varies inversely with the absolute pressure during a change of state.",
        choices: [
            "A. Daltons Law",
            "B. Charles' Law",
            "C. First Law of Thermodynamics",
            "D. Boyle's Law"
        ],
        answer: "D. Boyle's Law"
    },
    {
        question: "A unit of force that produces unit acceleration (in ft/s2) in a unit mass (in lbm)",
        choices: [
            "A. Poundal",
            "B. Pound",
            "C. Newton",
            "D. Dyne"
        ],
        answer: "A. Poundal"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following does not belong to the group?",
        choices: [
            "A. Potential Energy",
            "B. Kinetic Energy",
            "C. Heat Energy",
            "D. Flow energy"
        ],
        answer: "C. Heat Energy"
    },
    {
        question: "Why does a cube of ice float in water?",
        choices: [
            "A. Ice has lower temperature than water",
            "B. The density of ice is lesser than water",
            "C. There are more water than ice",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        answer: "B. The density of ice is lesser than water"
    },
    {
        question: "The work done in pushing a fluid across a boundary, usually into or out of a system is called",
        choices: [
            "A. Potential Energy",
            "B. Flow Energy",
            "C. Kinetic Energy",
            "D. Internal Energy"
        ],
        answer: "B. Flow Energy"
    },
    {
        question: "Energy balance for steady flow process is:",
        choices: [
            "A. Energy (in) = Energy (out)",
            "B. Energy (in) = change in total energy",
            "C. Energy (in) - Energy (out) = change in total energy",
            "D. Energy (in) + Energy (out) = change in total energy"
        ],
        answer: "A. Energy (in) = Energy (out)"
    },
    {
        question: "______ is a composite property applicable to all fluids and is defined by sum of internal energy and the product of pressure and volume",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat",
            "B. Work",
            "C. Enthalpy",
            "D. Total Work"
        ],
        answer: "C. Enthalpy"
    },
    {
        question: "States that energy is neither created nor destroyed; it can only change forms:",
        choices: [
            "A. Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics",
            "B. First Law of Thermodynamics",
            "C. Daltons Law",
            "D. Archimedes Principle"
        ],
        answer: "B. First Law of Thermodynamics"
    },
    {
        question: "Heat is defined as form of energy that is transferred between two systems by the virtue of a",
        choices: [
            "A. Pressure difference",
            "B. Mass difference",
            "C. Volume difference",
            "D. Temperature difference"
        ],
        answer: "D. Temperature difference"
    },
    {
        question: "The useful energy transfer in Bu/hr divided by input power in Watts. This is just the coefficient of performance expressed in mixed units.",
        choices: [
            "A. Energy efficiency ratio",
            "B. Coll efficiency",
            "C. Bypass factor",
            "D. Sensible heat ratio"
        ],
        answer: "A. Energy efficiency ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "If EER is the energy efficiency ratio, and COP is the coefficient of performance then",
        choices: [
            "A. EER = 3.41 COP",
            "B. COP = 3.41 EER",
            "C. EER x COP = 3.41",
            "D. 3.41 EER x COP = 1"
        ],
        answer: "A. EER = 3.41 COP"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a reversed Rankine vapor cycle?",
        choices: [
            "A. Carnot refrigeration cycle",
            "B. Vapor compression cycle",
            "C. Air refrigeration cycle",
            "D. Absorption cycle"
        ],
        answer: "B. Vapor compression cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "The most common type of refrigeration cycle, finding application in household refrigerators, air conditioners for cars and houses, chillers and so on.",
        choices: [
            "A. Carnot refrigeration cycle",
            "B. Vapor compression cycle",
            "C. Air refrigeration cycle",
            "D. Absorption cycle"
        ],
        answer: "B. Vapor compression cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a reversed Breyton cycle?",
        choices: [
            "A. Carnot refrigeration cycle",
            "B. Vapor compression cycle",
            "C. Air refrigeration cycle",
            "D. Absorption cycle"
        ],
        answer: "C. Air refrigeration cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following cycle is bulky and involves toxic fluids, hence it is unsuitable for home and autocooling.",
        choices: [
            "A. Carnot refrigeration cycle",
            "B. Absorption cycle",
            "C. Vapor compression cycle",
            "D. Air refrigeration cycle"
        ],
        answer: "B. Absorption cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following refrigeration cycle is practical when large quantities of waste or inexpensive heat energy are available.",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat driven refrigeration cycle",
            "B. Absorption cycle",
            "C. Vapor compression cycle",
            "D. Air refrigeration cycle"
        ],
        answer: "A. Heat driven refrigeration cycle"
    },
    {
        question: "A product of computer-aided manufacturing and precision machining, were introduced commercially in the late 1980's as replacements for reciprocating compressors in small residential air conditioners.",
        choices: [
            "A. Reciprocating compressors",
            "B. Centrifugal compressors",
            "C. Rotary compressors",
            "D. Scroll compressors"
        ],
        answer: "D. Scroll compressors"
    },
    {
        question: "Condensers used in small and medium sized, up to approximately 100 tons refrigerators.",
        choices: [
            "A. air-cooled condensers",
            "B. water cooled condensers",
            "C. high side condensers",
            "D. low side condensers"
        ],
        answer: "A. air-cooled condensers"
    },
    {
        question: "For efficient operation, the condensing temperature should not be lower than",
        choices: [
            "A. 5 C",
            "B. 17 C",
            "C. 10 C",
            "D. 20 C"
        ],
        answer: "A. 5 C"
    },
    {
        question: "For efficient operation, the condensing temperature should not be more than",
        choices: [
            "A. 5 C",
            "B. 17 C",
            "C. 10 C",
            "D. 20 C"
        ],
        answer: "B. 17 C"
    },
    {
        question: "Condensers used for larger capacities refrigerators.",
        choices: [
            "A. air-cooled condensers",
            "B. water-cooled condensers",
            "C. high side condensers",
            "D. low side condensers"
        ],
        answer: "B. water-cooled condensers"
    },
    {
        question: "Coolers and chillers for water generally operate with an average temperature difference of",
        choices: [
            "A. 3 to 11 C",
            "B. 5 to 8 C",
            "C. 6 to 22 C",
            "D. 10 to 16 C"
        ],
        answer: "A. 3 to 11 C"
    },
    {
        question: "To avoid freezing problems, entering refrigerant should be",
        choices: [
            "A. below - 2 C",
            "B. above - 2 C",
            "C. equal to - 2 C",
            "D. 0 C"
        ],
        answer: "B. above - 2 C"
    },
    {
        question: "Suction lines should not be sized too large, as a reasonable velocity is needed to carry oil from the evaporator back to the compressor. For horizontal suction lines, the recommended minimum velocity is",
        choices: [
            "A. 3.8 m/s",
            "B. 6.1m/s",
            "C. 7.1 m/s",
            "D. 4.8 m/s"
        ],
        answer: "A. 3.8 m/s"
    },
    {
        question: "Type of turbine used for low heads, high rotational speeds and larger flow rates",
        choices: [
            "A. axial flow turbines",
            "B. reaction turbines",
            "C. radial flow turbines",
            "D. impulse turbines"
        ],
        answer: "A. axial flow turbines"
    },
    {
        question: "To keep the deflected jet out of the way of the incoming jet, the actual angle is limited to approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 135 deg.",
            "B. 150 deg.",
            "C. 165 deg.",
            "D. 175 deg."
        ],
        answer: "C. 165 deg."
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following turbines are centrifugal pumps operating in reverse?",
        choices: [
            "A. Reaction turbines",
            "B. Impulse turbines",
            "C. Tangential turbines",
            "D. axial flow turbines"
        ],
        answer: "A. Reaction turbines"
    },
    {
        question: "Also known as Francis turbines or radial flow turbines",
        choices: [
            "A. Impulse turbines",
            "B. Tangential turbines",
            "C. Reaction turbines",
            "D. Axial flow turbines"
        ],
        answer: "C. Reaction turbines"
    },
    {
        question: "The turbine, draft tube and all related parts comprise what is known as",
        choices: [
            "A. powerhouse",
            "B. forbay",
            "C. setting",
            "D. surge chamber"
        ],
        answer: "C. setting"
    },
    {
        question: "When a forbay is not part of the generating plant's design, it will be desirable to provide a change in flowrate.",
        choices: [
            "A. forbay",
            "B. draft tube",
            "C. surge chamber",
            "D. penstock"
        ],
        answer: "C. surge chamber"
    },
    {
        question: "To keep the deflected jet out of the way of the incoming jet, the actual angle is limited to approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 90 deg.",
            "B. 135 deg.",
            "C. 165 %",
            "D. 175 deg."
        ],
        answer: "C. 165 %"
    },
    {
        question: "The minimum fluid energy required at the pump inlet for satisfactory operation is known as",
        choices: [
            "A. MPSHR",
            "B. MPSHA",
            "C. velocity head",
            "D. friction head"
        ],
        answer: "A. MPSHR"
    },
    {
        question: "Throttling the input line to a pump and venting or evacuating the receiving tank",
        choices: [
            "A. both increase cavitation",
            "B. both decrease cavitation",
            "C. both eliminate cavitation",
            "D. both drive cavitation"
        ],
        answer: "A. both increase cavitation"
    },
    {
        question: "Traditional reciprocating pumps with pistons and rods can be either single-acting or double acting and are suitable up to approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 2000 psi",
            "B. 4000 psi",
            "C. 8000 psi",
            "D. 10,000 psi"
        ],
        answer: "A. 2000 psi"
    },
    {
        question: "Runger pumps are only single-acting and are suitable up to approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 2000 psi",
            "B. 4000 psi",
            "C. 8000 psi",
            "D. 10,000 psi"
        ],
        answer: "D. 10,000 psi"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of the actual to the ideal heat transfer coefficient:",
        choices: [
            "A. fouling factor",
            "B. sensible heat ratio",
            "C. cleanliness factor",
            "D. Blot number"
        ],
        answer: "C. cleanliness factor"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of the maximum to minimum mass steam flow rates at which the temperature can be accurately contained by the desuperheater:",
        choices: [
            "A. cleanliness ratio",
            "B. capacity factor",
            "C. turndown ratio",
            "D. fouling factor"
        ],
        answer: "C. turndown ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "With a reversible regenerator, the thermal efficiency of the Ericsson cycle is ___ to that of the Carnot cycle",
        choices: [
            "A. less than",
            "B. greater than",
            "C. proportional",
            "D. equal"
        ],
        answer: "D. equal"
    },
    {
        question: "Used to described the act of blowing the exhaust product out with the air-fuel mixture",
        choices: [
            "A. supercharging",
            "B. scavenging",
            "C. honing",
            "D. choking"
        ],
        answer: "A. supercharging"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following compresses and increases the amount of air that enters the cylinder per stroke",
        choices: [
            "A. supercharging",
            "B. scavenging",
            "C. honing",
            "D. choking"
        ],
        answer: "A. supercharging"
    },
    {
        question: "A form of supercharging in which the exhaust gases drive the supercharger",
        choices: [
            "A. lugging",
            "B. honing",
            "C. turbocharging",
            "D. blower charging"
        ],
        answer: "C. turbocharging"
    },
    {
        question: "A closed heat exchanger that transfer heat from compressed air to cooler air.",
        choices: [
            "A. intercooler",
            "B. regenerator",
            "C. economizer",
            "D. aftercooler"
        ],
        answer: "D. aftercooler"
    },
    {
        question: "At the control stand, pitch of the turbine blades must be adjusted manually by a",
        choices: [
            "A. sensor",
            "B. float value",
            "C. gate",
            "D. switch"
        ],
        answer: "A. sensor"
    },
    {
        question: "The most commonly used adjustable-blade propeller turbine.",
        choices: [
            "A. Francis turbine",
            "B. Kaplan turbine",
            "C. Lithgow turbine",
            "D. Pelton wheel"
        ],
        answer: "B. Kaplan turbine"
    },
    {
        question: "Runner blades are adjusted automatically in synchronism with turbine widest gates by a/an",
        choices: [
            "A. control valve",
            "B. governor",
            "C. oil servomotor",
            "D. manual operation"
        ],
        answer: "C. oil servomotor"
    },
    {
        question: "What is supplied to the servomotor from the turbine governor oil system through the generator shaft and through a control valve.",
        choices: [
            "A. water",
            "B. air",
            "C. steam",
            "D. oil"
        ],
        answer: "D. oil"
    },
    {
        question: "Used to exhaust air from the casing for starting.",
        choices: [
            "A. ejectors",
            "B. operator",
            "C. injector",
            "D. blower"
        ],
        answer: "A. ejectors"
    },
    {
        question: "Advantageous for propeller turbines of all types",
        choices: [
            "A. open flume setting",
            "B. siphon setting",
            "C. cast setting",
            "D. capacity setting"
        ],
        answer: "B. siphon setting"
    },
    {
        question: "A turbine setting where one disadvantage is the difficulty of lubricating the operating mechanism, with consequent relatively rapid wear.",
        choices: [
            "A. siphon setting",
            "B. open flume setting",
            "C. cast setting",
            "D. capacity setting"
        ],
        answer: "B. open flume setting"
    },
    {
        question: "A patented device combining expansion and compression functions in a single rotor permitting higher cycle temperatures.",
        choices: [
            "A. Comprex",
            "B. compressor",
            "C. Expander",
            "D. single-shaft"
        ],
        answer: "A. Comprex"
    },
    {
        question: "A rough measure of the physical size of the equipment which must handle the specified quantity of the fluid",
        choices: [
            "A. pressure ratio",
            "B. fuel rate",
            "C. thermal efficiency",
            "D. Air rate"
        ],
        answer: "D. Air rate"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of the highest main compressor discharge pressure to the lowest main compressor inlet pressure",
        choices: [
            "A. cycle pressure ratio",
            "B. cycle pressure level",
            "C. work ratio",
            "D. Air rate"
        ],
        answer: "A. cycle pressure ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of the maximum pressure in the cycle to the atmospheric pressure",
        choices: [
            "A. cycle pressure ratio",
            "B. cycle pressure level",
            "C. regenerator effectiveness",
            "D. thermal efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "B. cycle pressure level"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of the actual partial pressure exerted by the water vapor in any volume of air to the partial pressure that would be exerted by the water vapor if the water vapor in the air is saturated at the temperature of the air",
        choices: [
            "A. relative humidity",
            "B. absolute humidity",
            "C. humidity ratio",
            "D. saturation ratio"
        ],
        answer: "A. relative humidity"
    },
    {
        question: "An expression of the mass of water vapor per unit mass of dry air",
        choices: [
            "A. relative humidity",
            "B. absolute humidity",
            "C. humidity ratio",
            "D. saturation ratio"
        ],
        answer: "C. humidity ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is equivalent to 1 lb ?",
        choices: [
            "A. 5000 grains",
            "B. 6000 grains",
            "C. 7000 grains",
            "D. 8000 grains"
        ],
        answer: "C. 7000 grains"
    },
    {
        question: "The locus of states that have the same value of stagnation enthalpy and mass flux is called.",
        choices: [
            "A. Fanno line",
            "B. Rayleigh Line",
            "C. Willan's line",
            "D. Moller's line"
        ],
        answer: "A. Fanno line"
    },
    {
        question: "Combining the conservation of mass and momentum equations into a single equation and plotting it on the h-s diagram yield a curve called",
        choices: [
            "A. Fanno line",
            "B. Rayleigh line",
            "C. Willan's line",
            "D. Moller's line"
        ],
        answer: "B. Rayleigh line"
    },
    {
        question: "Across the shock, the stagnation temperature of an ideal gas",
        choices: [
            "A. increases",
            "B. decreases",
            "C. remains constant",
            "D. proportional"
        ],
        answer: "C. remains constant"
    },
    {
        question: "The locus of points where condensation will take place regardless of the initial temperature and pressure at the nozzle entrance.",
        choices: [
            "A. Fanno line",
            "B. Rayleigh line",
            "C. Willan line",
            "D. Wilson line"
        ],
        answer: "D. Wilson line"
    },
    {
        question: "The enthalpy of a substance at a specified state due to its chemical composition.",
        choices: [
            "A. enthalpy of reaction",
            "B. enthalpy of combustion",
            "C. enthalpy of formation",
            "D. enthalpy of vaporization"
        ],
        answer: "C. enthalpy of formation"
    },
    {
        question: "Since the air-conditioning apparatus usually removes heat and moisture from both the conditioned room and from outside make-up air, the sensible heat ratio that can be used is",
        choices: [
            "A. Room sensible heat ratio",
            "B. Coll or Apparatus sensible heat ratio",
            "C. Grand sensible heat ratio",
            "D. Effective sensible heat ratio"
        ],
        answer: "C. Grand sensible heat ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "The slope of the line between the apparatus dewpoint on the saturation line and the design conditions of the conditioned space.",
        choices: [
            "A. Room sensible heat ratio",
            "B. Coll or Apparatus sensible heat ratio",
            "C. Grand sensible heat ratio",
            "D. Effective sensible heat ratio"
        ],
        answer: "D. Effective sensible heat ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "The sensible heat ratio is a",
        choices: [
            "A. sensible slope",
            "B. latent slope",
            "C. geometric slope",
            "D. psychrometric slope"
        ],
        answer: "D. psychrometric slope"
    },
    {
        question: "The percentage of the air that is not cooled or heated is",
        choices: [
            "A. bypass factor",
            "B. coil factor",
            "C. energy-efficiency ratio",
            "D. saturation ratio"
        ],
        answer: "A. bypass factor"
    },
    {
        question: "The bypass factors for large commercial units",
        choices: [
            "A. around 20%",
            "B. around 30%",
            "C. around 10%",
            "D. around 50%"
        ],
        answer: "C. around 10%"
    },
    {
        question: "The bypass factors for residential units are approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 10%",
            "B. 15%",
            "C. 25%",
            "D. 35%"
        ],
        answer: "D. 35%"
    },
    {
        question: "The complement of the bypass factor is",
        choices: [
            "A. Saturation ratio",
            "B. energy efficiency ratio",
            "C. coil efficiency",
            "D. grand efficiency"
        ],
        answer: "C. coil efficiency"
    },
    {
        question: "The mass of water sprayed to the mass of air passing through the washer per unit time",
        choices: [
            "A. humidification load",
            "B. spray ratio",
            "C. water vapor",
            "D. circulation ratio"
        ],
        answer: "B. spray ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "In a cooling tower, the water passes over staggered slats or interior fill, also known as",
        choices: [
            "A. shedding",
            "B. packing",
            "C. cellular",
            "D. polyvinyl"
        ],
        answer: "B. packing"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of total dissolved solids in the recirculating water to the total dissolved solids in the make-up water.",
        choices: [
            "A. ratio of concentration",
            "B. cooling efficiency",
            "C. coil efficiency",
            "D. bypass factor"
        ],
        answer: "A. ratio of concentration"
    },
    {
        question: "Through windage removes some of the solids, most must be removed by bleeding some of the water off. This is known as",
        choices: [
            "A. range",
            "B. approach",
            "C. direct",
            "D. bleed-off"
        ],
        answer: "D. bleed-off"
    },
    {
        question: "A dry-cooling tower where steam travels through large diameter 'trunks' to a cross-flow heat exchanger where it is condensed and cooled by the cooler air",
        choices: [
            "A. direct condensing tower",
            "B. indirect condensing dry cooling tower",
            "C. evaporative cooling tower",
            "D. atmospheric cooling tower"
        ],
        answer: "A. direct condensing tower"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the refrigerant 'of choice' in uniting air conditioners?",
        choices: [
            "A. R-22",
            "B. R-123",
            "C. R-11",
            "D. R-502"
        ],
        answer: "A. R-22"
    },
    {
        question: "In new equipment, which of the following replaces R-11?",
        choices: [
            "A. R-12",
            "B. R-123",
            "C. R-502",
            "D. R-22"
        ],
        answer: "B. R-123"
    },
    {
        question: "A New combustion turbines on the cutting edge of technology (Advanced turbine systems) are able to achieve",
        choices: [
            "A. 38 to 38.5 %",
            "B. 40 to 40.5 %",
            "C. 36 to 36.5 %",
            "D. 34 to 34.5 %"
        ],
        answer: "A. 38 to 38.5 %"
    },
    {
        question: "A regenerator is",
        choices: [
            "A. a counterflow heat exchanger",
            "B. a cross flow heat exchanger",
            "C. a mixed flow heat exchanger",
            "D. a parallel flow heat exchanger"
        ],
        answer: "C. a mixed flow heat exchanger"
    },
    {
        question: "How many percent of solar energy survives absorption and reflection?",
        choices: [
            "A. 40 to 70 %",
            "B. 50 to 80 %",
            "C. 30 to 60 %",
            "D. 20 to 50 %"
        ],
        answer: "A. 40 to 70 %"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following collectors use mirrors and/or lenses to focus the suns energy on a small absorber area.",
        choices: [
            "A. flat plate collectors",
            "B. concentrating collectors",
            "C. non focusing collectors",
            "D. evacuated tube collectors"
        ],
        answer: "C. non focusing collectors"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following collectors are useful when extremely hot transfer fluid is needed and are generally limited to commercial projects?",
        choices: [
            "A. flat plate collectors",
            "B. concentrating collectors",
            "C. focusing collectors",
            "D. evacuated tube collectors"
        ],
        answer: "D. evacuated tube collectors"
    },
    {
        question: "The ratio of energy absorbed by the transfer fluid to the original incident energy striking the collector.",
        choices: [
            "A. collector efficiency",
            "B. shading factor",
            "C. sun efficiency",
            "D. absorbance"
        ],
        answer: "A. collector efficiency"
    },
    {
        question: "The shading factor in calculating the heat absorbed by the solar collector has a value approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 0.95 to 0.97",
            "B. 0.75 to 0.77",
            "C. 0.85 to 0.87",
            "D. 0.65 to 0.67"
        ],
        answer: "A. 0.95 to 0.97"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following main approaches to solar energy generating systems describes that parabolic tracking trough concentrators focus sunlight on evacuated glass tubes that run along the collectors focal lines.",
        choices: [
            "A. trough electric system",
            "B. power tower system",
            "C. central receiver system",
            "D. dish/Sitting system"
        ],
        answer: "A. trough electric system"
    },
    {
        question: "Trough electric technology is relatively mature but due to the low temperatures, average annual thermal efficiencies are only",
        choices: [
            "A. 10 to 15 %",
            "B. 15 to 20 %",
            "C. 5 to 10 %",
            "D. 25 to 30 %"
        ],
        answer: "A. 10 to 15 %"
    },
    {
        question: "A field of heliostats or tracking mirrors concentrates solar energy onto a receiver on a central tower.",
        choices: [
            "A. trough electric system",
            "B. distributed collector system",
            "C. power tower system",
            "D. dish/Sitting system"
        ],
        answer: "B. distributed collector system"
    },
    {
        question: "In a power tower system typical thermal efficiencies is in the range",
        choices: [
            "A. 10 to 15 %",
            "B. 15 to 20 %",
            "C. 5 to 10 %",
            "D. 25 to 30 %"
        ],
        answer: "B. 15 to 20 %"
    },
    {
        question: "A flash steam cycle can be used if the hot water temperature is approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 165 C or higher",
            "B. 145 C to 200 C",
            "C. 150 C or higher",
            "D. below 200 C"
        ],
        answer: "A. 165 C or higher"
    },
    {
        question: "A binary cycle using a separate heat transfer fluid if the temperature of the hot water is between approximately",
        choices: [
            "A. 165 C and 120 C",
            "B. 225 C and 175 C",
            "C. 200 C and 150 C",
            "D. 300 C and higher"
        ],
        answer: "A. 165 C and 120 C"
    },
    {
        question: "In a hot rock systems, water is injected through injection wells into artificially made fractured rock beds of how many kilometers below the surface?",
        choices: [
            "A. 1 to 6 km",
            "B. 4 to 10 km",
            "C. 3 to 9 km",
            "D. 6 to 11 km"
        ],
        answer: "A. 1 to 6 km"
    },
    {
        question: "What temperature is required to ignite the fuel oil?",
        choices: [
            "A. 800 to 1000 F",
            "B. 900 to 1100 F",
            "C. 700 to 900 F",
            "D. 1000 to 1200 F"
        ],
        answer: "A. 800 to 1000 F"
    },
    {
        question: "What air pressure is required to produce the required ignition temperature?",
        choices: [
            "A. 350 to 500 psi",
            "B. 450 to 600 psi",
            "C. 250 to 400 psi",
            "D. 150 to 300 psi"
        ],
        answer: "A. 350 to 500 psi"
    },
    {
        question: "The portion of the piston which extends below the piston pin and serves as a guide for the piston and connecting rod.",
        choices: [
            "A. piston skirt",
            "B. piston scoring",
            "C. piston ring",
            "D. piston seizure"
        ],
        answer: "A. piston skirt"
    },
    {
        question: "Binding of the piston and the cylinder wall as a result of the lubrication having been destroyed by excessive temperature and friction.",
        choices: [
            "A. piston skirt",
            "B. piston scoring",
            "C. piston ring",
            "D. piston seizure"
        ],
        answer: "D. piston seizure"
    },
    {
        question: "A combination of liquids which do not mix – or combine chemically.",
        choices: [
            "A. emulsion",
            "B. evaporation",
            "C. deposition",
            "D. separation"
        ],
        answer: "A. emulsion"
    },
    {
        question: "At what temperature will self-igniting cartridges ignite?",
        choices: [
            "A. About 200 F",
            "B. About 210 F",
            "C. About 190 F",
            "D. About 250 F"
        ],
        answer: "C. About 190 F"
    },
    {
        question: "The fuel is supplied by one pump and switched to each cylinder by a multi outlet rotating valve or distributor.",
        choices: [
            "A. distributor system",
            "B. non injector system",
            "C. injector system",
            "D. non distributor system"
        ],
        answer: "A. distributor system"
    },
    {
        question: "A chamber so designed that injection takes place directly opposite its outlet, the chamber extending backward from the outlet.",
        choices: [
            "A. pre combustion chamber",
            "B. ante combustion chamber",
            "C. separate combustion chamber",
            "D. air cell chamber"
        ],
        answer: "B. ante combustion chamber"
    },
    {
        question: "A cylindrical vessel connected in the fuel system to absorb the shock of the injection pumps and to provide a reservoir at high pressure for supplying an even flow of fuel oil to the cylinders.",
        choices: [
            "A. absorber",
            "B. governor",
            "C. accumulator",
            "D. injector"
        ],
        answer: "C. accumulator"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used to improve cold weather starting?",
        choices: [
            "A. poppet valve",
            "B. check valve",
            "C. glow plug",
            "D. spark plug"
        ],
        answer: "C. glow plug"
    },
    {
        question: "The rated power that the manufacturer claims the engine is able to provide on a continuous basis without incurring damage.",
        choices: [
            "A. brakepower",
            "B. intermittent rating",
            "C. continuous duty rating",
            "D. power rating"
        ],
        answer: "C. continuous duty rating"
    },
    {
        question: "The peak power that can be produced on an occasional basis.",
        choices: [
            "A. brakepower",
            "B. intermittent rating",
            "C. continuous duty rating",
            "D. power rating"
        ],
        answer: "B. intermittent rating"
    },
    {
        question: "A value of a property that includes the effect of friction is known as",
        choices: [
            "A. brake value",
            "B. indicated value",
            "C. friction value",
            "D. actual value"
        ],
        answer: "A. brake value"
    },
    {
        question: "Forced draft fans are run at relatively high speeds in the range of",
        choices: [
            "A. 1200 to 1800 rpm",
            "B. 1500 to 2000 rpm",
            "C. 1000 to 1600 rpm",
            "D. 900 to 1500 rpm"
        ],
        answer: "A. 1200 to 1800 rpm"
    },
    {
        question: "Chimneys that rely on natural draft are sometimes referred to as",
        choices: [
            "A. natural chimney",
            "B. normal chimney",
            "C. gravity chimney",
            "D. stack"
        ],
        answer: "C. gravity chimney"
    },
    {
        question: "For realistic problems, the achievable stack effect probably should be considered to be",
        choices: [
            "A. 75 % of the ideal",
            "B. equal to the ideal",
            "C. 80 % of the ideal",
            "D. half the ideal"
        ],
        answer: "C. 80 % of the ideal"
    },
    {
        question: "In a balanced system, the available draft is",
        choices: [
            "A. unity",
            "B. 100",
            "C. zero",
            "D. infinite"
        ],
        answer: "C. zero"
    },
    {
        question: "It is a device used for atomizing or cracking fuel oil and through which the fuel oil is injected into the working cylinders of Diesel engines.",
        choices: [
            "A. atomizer",
            "B. injector",
            "C. fuel spray nozzle",
            "D. cracker"
        ],
        answer: "A. atomizer"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the proper seat width of a spray valve?",
        choices: [
            "A. 1/16 in.",
            "B. 1/32 in.",
            "C. 1/8 in.",
            "D. 1/4 in."
        ],
        answer: "A. 1/16 in."
    },
    {
        question: "A device which automatically governs or controls the speed of an engine.",
        choices: [
            "A. servomotor",
            "B. indicator",
            "C. governor",
            "D. speedometer"
        ],
        answer: "C. governor"
    },
    {
        question: "The term enthalpy",
        choices: [
            "A. is only used for the properties of refrigerant vapor.",
            "B. is considered by Gibb's Rule.",
            "C. will measure, by its change, the quantity of heat added when refrigerant is vaporized at constant pressure.",
            "D. defines the gas equation."
        ],
        answer: "C. will measure, by its change, the quantity of heat added when refrigerant is vaporized at constant pressure."
    },
    {
        question: "When heat is added to moist air in an air – conditioning process",
        choices: [
            "A. the wet – bulb temperature decreases.",
            "B. the water vapor pressure increases.",
            "C. the relative humidity increases.",
            "D. the absolute humidity remains constant"
        ],
        answer: "D. the absolute humidity remains constant"
    },
    {
        question: "Air having a relative humidity of 50% is heated in an air conditioning apparatus. After having it will be found that.",
        choices: [
            "A. its relative humidity will be lower than 50%.",
            "B. its relative humidity will be higher than 50%.",
            "C. its vapor pressure will decrease.",
            "D. its absolute humidity remains constant."
        ],
        answer: "D. its absolute humidity remains constant."
    },
    {
        question: "The ton of refrigeration is a heat unit equivalent to",
        choices: [
            "A. 3/413 BTU/hr",
            "B. 2/545 BTU/hr",
            "C. 990 BTU/hr",
            "D. 12,000 BTU/hr"
        ],
        answer: "D. 12,000 BTU/hr"
    },
    {
        question: "In the process of heating atmospheric air in an air conditioning apparatus",
        choices: [
            "A. the relative humidity increases.",
            "B. the relative humidity remains constant.",
            "C. the water vapor pressure decreases.",
            "D. the absolute or specific humidity remains constant."
        ],
        answer: "D. the absolute or specific humidity remains constant."
    },
    {
        question: "The temperature at which the vapor in mixture is cooled at constant pressure is called",
        choices: [
            "A. Dry - bulb temperature",
            "B. Wet - bulb temperature",
            "C. Dew – point temperature",
            "D. Relative humidity"
        ],
        answer: "C. Dew – point temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "Refers to the amount of air that has not been in contact, during the sensible cooling process, with the surface of the cooler coil.",
        choices: [
            "A. Coil efficiency",
            "B. Coil contact factor",
            "C. Coll by - pass factor",
            "D. None of these"
        ],
        answer: "C. Coll by - pass factor"
    },
    {
        question: "The process that the body uses to convert energy in food to heat and work, or the process that determines the rate at which energy is converted from chemical to thermal form within the body.",
        choices: [
            "A. Metabolism",
            "B. Eating",
            "C. Body food processing",
            "D. Blood circulation"
        ],
        answer: "A. Metabolism"
    },
    {
        question: "It is a body insulation that is usually described as a single equivalent uniform layer over the whole body.",
        choices: [
            "A. Skin",
            "B. Blood",
            "C. Clothing",
            "D. Water"
        ],
        answer: "C. Clothing"
    },
    {
        question: "Mean radiant temperature is the basic index used to describe the radiant conditions in a space, it is the mean temperature of individual exposed surfaces in the environment.",
        choices: [
            "A. Index temperature",
            "B. Mean radiant temperature",
            "C. Space temperature",
            "D. Dry - bulb temperature"
        ],
        answer: "B. Mean radiant temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the most common instrument used to determine the main radiant temperature. It consists of a hollow sphere 6 inches in diameter, flat black paint coating, and a thermocouple or thermometer bulb at its center.",
        choices: [
            "A. Psychrometer",
            "B. Mercury thermometer",
            "C. Vernon's globe thermometer",
            "D. Kelvin's thermometer"
        ],
        answer: "C. Vernon's globe thermometer"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the mechanism of heat transfer between parts of a continuum because of transfer of energy between particles or groups of particles at the atomic level. It is the mode of heat transmission through the building structure, like the wall, due to the temperature difference between surfaces of the wall.",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat transmission",
            "B. Thermal conduction",
            "C. Solar radiation",
            "D. Thermal convection"
        ],
        answer: "B. Thermal conduction"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the transport of energy by mixing in addition to conduction. It is associated with fluids in motion, generally through a pipe or duct or along a surface.",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat transmission",
            "B. Thermal conduction",
            "C. Solar radiation",
            "D. Thermal convection"
        ],
        answer: "D. Thermal convection"
    },
    {
        question: "A form of thermal convection when the bulk of the fluid is moving relative to the heat transfer surface because such motion is usually caused by a blower, fan, or pump that is forcing the flow.",
        choices: [
            "A. Slow convection",
            "B. Forced convection",
            "C. Free convection",
            "D. Thermal convection"
        ],
        answer: "B. Forced convection"
    },
    {
        question: "A form of thermal convection when the motion of the fluid is due entirely to buoyancy forces, usually confined to a layer near the heated or cooled surface.",
        choices: [
            "A. Slow convection",
            "B. Forced convection",
            "C. Free convection",
            "D. Thermal convection"
        ],
        answer: "C. Free convection"
    },
    {
        question: "A mode of heat transfer by electromagnetic waves, an entirely different phenomenon from conduction and convection; it can occur in a perfect vacuum and is usually impeded by an intervening medium.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermal radiation",
            "B. Thermal conduction",
            "C. Solar radiation",
            "D. Thermal convection"
        ],
        answer: "B. Thermal conduction"
    },
    {
        question: "An enveloped area with significantly higher rate of heat transfer than the contaguous enclosure is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. Air condition room",
            "B. Thermal bridge",
            "C. Global irradiation",
            "D. Fenestration"
        ],
        answer: "A. Air condition room"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the total thermal radiation that impinges on a surface from all directions and from all sources.",
        choices: [
            "A. Adsorption",
            "B. Thermal bridge",
            "C. Total or global irradiation",
            "D. Transmission"
        ],
        answer: "C. Total or global irradiation"
    },
    {
        question: "The transformation of the radiant energy into thermal energy stored by the molecules is known as",
        choices: [
            "A. Absorption",
            "B. Transmission",
            "C. Radiation",
            "D. Reflection"
        ],
        answer: "C. Radiation"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the return of radiation by a surface without change of frequency; the radiation is 'bounced' off of the surface.",
        choices: [
            "A. Absorption",
            "B. Transmission",
            "C. Fenestration",
            "D. Reflection"
        ],
        answer: "D. Reflection"
    },
    {
        question: "In a refrigeration system, the heat absorbed in the evaporator per kg refrigerant passing through",
        choices: [
            "A. equals the increase in enthalpy.",
            "B. equals the increase in volume.",
            "C. does not depend on the refrigerant used.",
            "D. is decreased if pre-cooler is used."
        ],
        answer: "A. equals the increase in enthalpy."
    },
    {
        question: "It is the passage of radiation through a medium without change of frequency.",
        choices: [
            "A. Absorption",
            "B. Transmission",
            "C. Fenestation",
            "D. Reflection"
        ],
        answer: "B. Transmission"
    },
    {
        question: "It refers to any glazed aperture in a building envelope, the components of which include: glazing material, either glass or plastic; framing, mullions, murrins, and dividers; external shading devices; and integral shading systems (between glass).",
        choices: [
            "A. Absorption",
            "B. Transmission",
            "C. Fenestation",
            "D. Radiation"
        ],
        answer: "C. Fenestation"
    },
    {
        question: "The rate at which energy is transferred to or generated within a space is called:",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat transmission",
            "B. Heat conduction",
            "C. Heat gain",
            "D. Sensible heat convection"
        ],
        answer: "C. Heat gain"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the rate at which energy must be removed from a space to maintain the temperature and humidity at the design values.",
        choices: [
            "A. Heating load",
            "B. Heat conduction",
            "C. Heat gain",
            "D. Cooling load"
        ],
        answer: "D. Cooling load"
    },
    {
        question: "A it is the rate at which energy is removed from a space by cooling and dehumidifying equipment. This rate must be equal to the cooling load when the space conditions are constant and the equipment is operating.",
        choices: [
            "A. Heat transmission rate",
            "B. Heat extraction rate",
            "C. Heat gain rate",
            "D. Heat conduction rate"
        ],
        answer: "B. Heat extraction rate"
    },
    {
        question: "It is a computer or hand calculation procedure where energy requirements are determined at many outdoor temperature conditions. It is used for the energy calculations of air conditioning systems.",
        choices: [
            "A. Vernon method",
            "B. Bin method",
            "C. Kelvin method",
            "D. Dalton method"
        ],
        answer: "B. Bin method"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the temperature of a uniform environment at 100% relative humidity in which a person or occupant loses the same total amount of heat from the skin as in the actual environment.",
        choices: [
            "A. Humid operative temperature",
            "B. Mean temperature",
            "C. Mean radiant temperature",
            "D. All of these"
        ],
        answer: "A. Humid operative temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the ratio of the total evaporative heat loss required for thermal equilibrium to the maximum evaporative heat loss possible for the environment, multiplied by 100, for the steady - state conditions, and with the skin temperature constant at 95 °F.",
        choices: [
            "A. Temperature index",
            "B. Heat stress index",
            "C. Sensible heat index",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        answer: "B. Heat stress index"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the temperature of a uniform environment at 0% relative humidity in which a person or occupant loses the same total amount of heat from the skin as in the actual environment.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dry - bulb temperature",
            "B. Mean temperature",
            "C. Adiabatic equivalent temperature",
            "D. Wet - bulb globe temperature"
        ],
        answer: "C. Adiabatic equivalent temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "A Heat added to or removed from a substance that cause a change of temperature:",
        choices: [
            "A. absolute heat",
            "B. specific heat",
            "C. latent heat",
            "D. sensible heat"
        ],
        answer: "D. sensible heat"
    },
    {
        question: "It is an environment heat stress index that combines the dry - bulb temperature, a naturally ventilated wet - bulb temperature, and the globe temperature.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dry - bulb globe temperature",
            "B. Mean radiant temperature",
            "C. Adiabatic equivalent temperature",
            "D. Wet - bulb globe temperature"
        ],
        answer: "D. Wet - bulb globe temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "It is an empirical index for the combined effect of wind and low temperature.",
        choices: [
            "A. Temperature index",
            "B. Heat stress index",
            "C. Wind chill index",
            "D. Sensible heat index"
        ],
        answer: "C. Wind chill index"
    },
    {
        question: "A method of air handling to an air conditioned room that produces more economical performance as compared with systems where reheat might be required is called.",
        choices: [
            "A. One hundred percent outdoor air",
            "B. Air washing system",
            "C. Recirculated air with external bypass",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        answer: "C. Recirculated air with external bypass"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the ratio of the air humidity ratio to the humidity ratio of saturated air at the same temperature.",
        choices: [
            "A. Relative humidity",
            "B. Specific humidity",
            "C. Percent saturation",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        answer: "C. Percent saturation"
    },
    {
        question: "It is the ratio of the actual partial pressure of vapor and the saturation pressure of vapor corresponding to the actual temperature of the mixture.",
        choices: [
            "A. Relative humidity",
            "B. Specific humidity",
            "C. Humidity ratio",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        answer: "C. Humidity ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "Heat gain or heat loss due to a temperature difference across a building element is .",
        choices: [
            "A. Transmission",
            "B. Solar",
            "C. Infiltration",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        answer: "A. Transmission"
    },
    {
        question: "One ton of refrigeration is equivalent to",
        choices: [
            "A. 12,000 BTU/hr",
            "B. 50.4 kcal/min",
            "C. 200 BTU/min",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        answer: "D. All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Air whose condition is such that any decrease in temperature will result in condensation of the water vapor into liquid.",
        choices: [
            "A. Moist air",
            "B. Dry air",
            "C. Saturated air",
            "D. Unsaturated air"
        ],
        answer: "C. Saturated air"
    },
    {
        question: "A binary mixture of dry air and water vapor is known as:",
        choices: [
            "A. Moist air",
            "B. Dry air",
            "C. Saturated air",
            "D. Unsaturated air"
        ],
        answer: "A. Moist air"
    },
    {
        question: "In compressing air in water – jacketed air compressor, the power required to drive it",
        choices: [
            "A. is independent of the quantity of water circulated, for given pressure range.",
            "B. does not depend on the pressure range.",
            "C. depends on the temperature change of the air for a given pressure range.",
            "D. only depends on the exponent of the re – expansion valve."
        ],
        answer: "C. depends on the temperature change of the air for a given pressure range."
    },
    {
        question: "An instrument used in the study of the properties of air.",
        choices: [
            "A. Thermometer",
            "B. Psychrometer",
            "C. Hydrometer",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        answer: "C. Hydrometer"
    },
    {
        question: "The difference between dry–bulb and wet – bulb temperatures.",
        choices: [
            "A. Wet-bulb depression",
            "B. Cooling approach",
            "C. Dry–bulb difference",
            "D. Cooling range"
        ],
        answer: "A. Wet-bulb depression"
    },
    {
        question: "The transmission of heat from one place to another by fluid circulation between spots of different temperature is called.",
        choices: [
            "A. Convection",
            "B. Radiation",
            "C. Conservation",
            "D. Conduction"
        ],
        answer: "A. Convection"
    },
    {
        question: "A machine or equipment used for drying process.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dewaterer",
            "B. Dryer",
            "C. Evaporator",
            "D. Filter"
        ],
        answer: "B. Dryer"
    },
    {
        question: "Water occurring when chemical component of the material changes its chemical composition by heat or other means is called.",
        choices: [
            "A. Moisture",
            "B. Water vapor",
            "C. Steam",
            "D. Chemically combined water"
        ],
        answer: "D. Chemically combined water"
    },
    {
        question: "A wet – type mechanical classifier (solids separator) in which solids settle out of the carrier liquid and are concentrated for recovery is known as:",
        choices: [
            "A. Dewaterer",
            "B. Dryer",
            "C. Evaporator",
            "D. Filter"
        ],
        answer: "A. Dewaterer"
    },
    {
        question: "A term used for describing the moisture in the mass that is not on the surface of the material.",
        choices: [
            "A. Moisture content",
            "B. Vapor",
            "C. Inherent moisture",
            "D. Chemically combined water"
        ],
        answer: "C. Inherent moisture"
    },
    {
        question: "The main principle of the term drying process.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dewatering",
            "B. Water removal",
            "C. Evaporation",
            "D. Compression"
        ],
        answer: "C. Evaporation"
    },
    {
        question: "The common term for processes using only pressure, suction, or decantation.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dewatering",
            "B. Drying",
            "C. Evaporation",
            "D. Decantation"
        ],
        answer: "A. Dewatering"
    },
    {
        question: "The process of removing moisture in varying amounts from solid or semi – fluid materials; the process may be accomplished by pressure, suction, decantation, or evaporation.",
        choices: [
            "A. Dewatering",
            "B. Drying",
            "C. Evaporation",
            "D. Decantation"
        ],
        answer: "B. Drying"
    }
];

let currentIndex = 0;
let cardOrder = [];
let isFlipped = false;

// Initialize card order randomly
function initializeCards() {
    cardOrder = Array.from({ length: flashcardsData.length }, (_, i) => i);
    shuffleArray(cardOrder);
    displayCard();
    updateCounter();
    updateProgress();
}

// Shuffle array using Fisher-Yates algorithm
function shuffleArray(array) {
    for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
        const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
        [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]];
    }
}

// Display current card
function displayCard() {
    const cardIndex = cardOrder[currentIndex];
    const card = flashcardsData[cardIndex];

    document.getElementById('question-text').textContent = card.question;

    const choicesList = document.getElementById('choices-list');
    choicesList.innerHTML = card.choices.map(choice => `<li>${choice}</li>`).join('');

    document.getElementById('answer-text').textContent = card.answer;

    // Reset flip state
    const flashcard = document.getElementById('flashcard');
    flashcard.classList.remove('flipped');
    isFlipped = false;

    // Update button states
    updateButtons();
}

// Flip card
function flipCard() {
    const flashcard = document.getElementById('flashcard');
    flashcard.classList.toggle('flipped');
    isFlipped = !isFlipped;
}

// Next card
function nextCard() {
    if (currentIndex < cardOrder.length - 1) {
        currentIndex++;
        displayCard();
        updateCounter();
        updateProgress();
    }
}

// Previous card
function previousCard() {
    if (currentIndex > 0) {
        currentIndex--;
        displayCard();
        updateCounter();
        updateProgress();
    }
}

// Shuffle cards
function shuffleCards() {
    shuffleArray(cardOrder);
    currentIndex = 0;
    displayCard();
    updateCounter();
    updateProgress();
}

// Update counter
function updateCounter() {
    document.getElementById('current-card').textContent = currentIndex + 1;
    document.getElementById('total-cards').textContent = flashcardsData.length;
}

// Update progress bar
function updateProgress() {
    const progress = ((currentIndex + 1) / flashcardsData.length) * 100;
    document.getElementById('progress-fill').style.width = progress + '%';
}

// Update button states
function updateButtons() {
    const prevBtn = document.getElementById('prev-btn');
    const nextBtn = document.getElementById('next-btn');

    prevBtn.disabled = currentIndex === 0;
    nextBtn.disabled = currentIndex === cardOrder.length - 1;
}

// Keyboard navigation
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
    if (e.key === 'ArrowLeft') {
        previousCard();
    } else if (e.key === 'ArrowRight') {
        nextCard();
    } else if (e.key === ' ' || e.key === 'Enter') {
        e.preventDefault();
        flipCard();
    }
});

// Initialize on page load
initializeCards();